<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United Kingdom on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/united-kingdom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in United Kingdom on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/united-kingdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Message from John Cleese to the Citizens of the US</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/to-the-citizens-of-the-united-states-of-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/to-the-citizens-of-the-united-states-of-america/</guid>
      <description>I saw this somewhere on the internet and found it hilarious. I apologise to any US citizen if he/she is offended but this is really good!
 To The citizens of the United States of America :
In light of your failure to nominate competent candidates for President of the USA and thus to govern yourselves, we hereby give notice of the revocation of your independence, effective immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Queen to visit Slovenia</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</guid>
      <description>I was very surprised to hear that the British Queen Elisabeth II . is to visit Slovenia soon.
 Buckingham Palace press releases
ANNOUNCEMENT OF STATE VISITS TO SLOVENIA AND SLOVAKIA
26 June 2008
THE FOLLOWING STATEMENT IS ISSUED BY THE PRESS SECRETARY TO THE QUEEN
 T&amp;gt; he Queen and The Duke of Edinburgh will pay State Visits to: Slovenia, at the invitation of President Dr Danilo Tuerk ; and Slovakia , at the invitation of President Ivan Gasparovic , during this Autumn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive London for a day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I did what I wanted to do for a long while - to actually skydive in the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting it off for a long time, lately mostly due to the weather we have been having. Last weekend the weather was OK, no flu lingering in the background and no lameness in any of the legs :-) The Skydive London dropzone is situated about 3 hours drive away from Haverfordwest , adjacent to the town of Swindon .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
