<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Filming locations on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/filming-locations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Filming locations on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 19:06:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/filming-locations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Filming Snow White and the Huntsman at Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/filming-snow-white-and-the-huntsman-at-marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 19:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/filming-snow-white-and-the-huntsman-at-marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>After seeing the filming of Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows and Robin Hood on the Freshwater West beach, Third Star in Barafundle Bay we have again the film crews back in Pembrokeshire for the filming of Snow White and the Huntsman on my favourite beach Marloes Sands .
Filming should be around September 26th - 29th and should mainly involve filming of about 80 horses galloping towards a computer generated castle on Gateholm island .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robin Hood filmset all ready at Freshwater West</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/robin-hood-filmset-all-ready-at-freshwater-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 06:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/robin-hood-filmset-all-ready-at-freshwater-west/</guid>
      <description>Second location at the south Freshwater West carpark
  Had the opportunity to have a walk from Angle to the Freshwater West beach and it looks the production team has a lot of logistics to deal with. They seem to have chosen two locations to pitch-up marquees, one is just of the turn from the road to Angle on B4320 and B4319. The second, you could say the main, location is right next to the beach at the southern carpark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 07:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>I have tried to visit this place before but the last time got a bit disappointed as there was the standard parking fee . Today was a very good time to see the place, sunny and not a lot of people on it. Oh yes, and the parking was free. By the way, I am all for conservation and good old cash goes a long way in conservation but ripping local of so that they can use the local nature is just wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
