<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motorcycling on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/motorcycling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motorcycling on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 19:05:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/motorcycling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Puncture prevented further training</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/puncture-prevented-further-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 19:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/puncture-prevented-further-training/</guid>
      <description>I had a bit of an eventful day today. Set of to hike up Pen y fan , had to find a way out of town as there were was a road closure and ended up going a way I don&amp;rsquo;t usually use. Somewhere on that trip I must have ridden over something sharp. By the time I got to Leominster about 20 minutes away I felt the bike being unstable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great evening autumnal joyride near Brockhampton and the river Wye</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/a-great-evening-autumnal-joyride-near-brockhampton-and-the-river-wye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/a-great-evening-autumnal-joyride-near-brockhampton-and-the-river-wye/</guid>
      <description>Moving to Herefordshire was one of the more challenging things to do but its lovely to see how beautiful the countryside can be.
  All Saints’ Church, Brockhampton
            Near Bromyard
    Malvern Hills, Ragged Stone
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luggage FUBAR riding a motorcycle</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2014/luggage-fubar-riding-a-motorcycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 17:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2014/luggage-fubar-riding-a-motorcycle/</guid>
      <description>Had a great trip to the Algarve recently and rented a Honda Shadow motorcycle for a week. On one of the last few days of my stay there I planned a trip to the south-western tip of Portugal - Cabo de São Vicente and Sagres. However all did not go well from my start in Albufeira. As I knew I was going to be on the road for at least an hour, perhaps 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riding the Honda GL1800 Goldwing</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/riding-the-honda-gl1800-goldwing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 08:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/riding-the-honda-gl1800-goldwing/</guid>
      <description>As the year has been coming to an end and winter seems just round the corner I decided to fill some of my inter-locuming days with a bit of biking. Hired a bike but this time something a little more comfy for the longer journeys - a proper touring bike with heated arm rests and seats would you believe it!! This time I rented a touring bike from the same Manchester rental company I used before .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dodging storm clouds</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/dodging-storm-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/dodging-storm-clouds/</guid>
      <description>I guess a lot of seasoned bikers are familiar this skill but I had to develop olit completely from scratch and it was up to necessity rather than fancying myself taking on a skill I might not use ever again.
During my few weeks biking in the US this June I got quite good at it. What it basically is that as a motorcyclist you try avoiding getting wet by avoiding rainy clouds as they intercept your route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avenue of the Giants</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/avenue-of-the-giants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/avenue-of-the-giants/</guid>
      <description>The name sounds like something from a children&amp;rsquo;s adventure book, perhaps depicting an overgrown legume, but this was an actually road-sign I saw in northern California that was inviting me to leave the route 101 and explore its mysteries.
This is actually the name of a byway, a road that runs close to the Route 101 but is much MUCH nicer. The roads twists and rolls round enormous Redwood trees, which are really sequoia trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My biking retrospective</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/my-biking-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/my-biking-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>End of the trip in Chicago, Illinois
Today marked the first week since I hit the road. It seems like ages since I departed Chicago and I must say the trip has given me the desired effect and changed my perspective on biking and bikers. Long I thought them to be criminal gang associated thugs. But the truth really is far faaar from that misconception. They are a really friendly bunch of people that will always help each-other in trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of the road</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-end-of-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 20:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-end-of-the-road/</guid>
      <description>Distance travelled: ~8,000 miles (just under 13,000 km)
The 17 states that I had a chance to see:
 Illinois Milwaukee (briefly) Minessota (briefly) North Dakota South Dakota Wyoming Montana Idaho (briefly) Washington Oregon California Nevada Arizona Utah Colorado (briefly) Nebraska (briefly) Iowa (briefly)  People met: loads
Technical issues with the motorcycle: almost none, substantial oil addition in Utah at about 6.125 miles into trip. When I wrote this article I seemed to have completely forgotten about my problem getting the bike started on Day 1, when I was still on the Eaglerider carpark in Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 19:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/chicago/</guid>
      <description>Chicago river from Lower North Lakeshore drive
Drove from Morris, Illinois in the morning straight downtown. Although sometimes glitchy the built-in Android turn-by-turn satnav saved the day by giving me good verbal instructions to guide me to the Monaco hotel where I stayed until my flight on Tuesday. Left most of the luggage there and then drove to the Eaglerider shop at the Chicago, Countryside Harley-Davidson branch. Very thrilling ride but not that difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quick run towards Chicago</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-quick-run-towards-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-quick-run-towards-chicago/</guid>
      <description>After completing my wish of seeing the Grand Canyon I realized I need to start towards Chicago. The day before sort of already was a travel east but it was more south-east than northeast which it should have been. I started from the Colorado town of Grand Junction . The previous day travel was not pleasant at all. More like excruciatingly hot. It felt like I was in a stove and the air just kept getting hotter and there was no way of getting out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/grand-canyon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 02:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/grand-canyon/</guid>
      <description>And this was the penultimate final destination on my trip. Amaaaazing and truly awe inspiring. Those who have seen it probably know what I mean. Just the size of the whole landscape really gets you.
I was really on my way to Chicago but after sleeping on my thoughts when I was in St. George in Utah I decided to give it a go. I was going to go to the horseshoe but the local road was closed for roadworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death Valley, Las Vegas and the Hoover dam - 4 states in one day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/death-valley-las-vegas-and-the-hoover-dam-4-states-in-one-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 04:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/death-valley-las-vegas-and-the-hoover-dam-4-states-in-one-day/</guid>
      <description>Road down Deat Valley
Decided to give it a go and hope it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bite me in the backside if I turn out to be late for my bike drop-off on Saturday I. Chicago. I decided I really wanted to see at least some of Grand Canyon and I went for it. From Bishop in California I headed southeast towards Las Vegas by crossing the &amp;ldquo;infamous&amp;rdquo; Death Valley. In fact its not that scary and there is even a small basic petrol station and motel there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and the Yosemite national park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/san-francisco-and-the-yosemite-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 05:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/san-francisco-and-the-yosemite-national-park/</guid>
      <description>Yosemite national park
  I put these two together as I visited them on the same day. They are only about 4 hours drive from each other. I started the day in Santa Rosa and headed down highway 101 that leads into San Francisco over the Golden Gate bridge. The bridge always used to be a toll one as I recall but now they have a silly electronic system where your plate is scanned and then your account gets charged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/oregon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/oregon/</guid>
      <description>Not one of the very impressive days on my trip. The weather precipitation radar was showing quite a lot of scattered activity in the whole northwestern quarter of Oregon. I did have a little wish to see Mount St. Helens where that big eruption happened in 1980. This would actually take me northeast to my then position in Vancouver (yes, there is one in the state of Washington. So this plan was scrapped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redwood forests of northern California</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/redwood-forests-of-northern-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/redwood-forests-of-northern-california/</guid>
      <description>So now I am in lala land. OK. A bit mean of me and certainly not fair to generalise a specific entertainment made in a particular part of Los Angeles to the whole state of California. So far the surroundings are mesmerising. Its like riding in a scene of Jurassic park. Not even sure why they didn&amp;rsquo;t film the outdoor scenes here. Come to think of it, where did they film those scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 05:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/seattle/</guid>
      <description>Travel by ferry to Port Townsend. Olympic mountains not as impressive as thought but to prove me wrong would take to much time. Also the weather got worse so I had to go to a hotel for the night. The camp in Port Angeles was not really tent friendly. No soil to talk off, just a few centimetres, the coming storm would have blown my tent far away. So decided to cut my stay in the area short and took the ferry from Bainbridge island to downtown Seattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier national park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/glacier-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 15:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/glacier-national-park/</guid>
      <description>The previous day saw me hit the road big time as I rode from Yellowstone right up to St. Mary&amp;rsquo;s - a little town on the eastern entrance to the Glacier NP. My plan was to drive up the Road to the Sun over Logan&amp;rsquo;s pass. Unfortunately the road was closed due to all the snow that had to be cleared only to then have to do roadworks it in the few months that were left to do it in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cascade mountains</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-cascade-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 15:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-cascade-mountains/</guid>
      <description>After staying in a great KOA campsite in Winthrop, Washington, I took the road across the Cascade mountains. The scenery was similar to the Going to the Sun road in Montana. Very stunning mountain scenery, lakes, waterfalls &amp;hellip; it had everything. Unfortunately i didn&amp;rsquo;t see any bears but I was told they are frequently seen on the road.
Stopped for a cup of coffee on the way and took the ferry crossing to Port Townsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone national park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/yellowstone-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 13:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/yellowstone-national-park/</guid>
      <description>Day 8 was a travelling day from Rapid city, SD to Cody in Wyoming on the entrance to Yellowstone national park. Got lost a little in Worland and took an unwilling detour through a town called Thermopolis.
Didn&amp;rsquo;t find a suitable camp so I took a room in a motel. And just by chance I found this charming lodge called the Grizzly Lodge in a small town of Silver Gate. This town is somewhat in the middle of nowhere, tucked between the hills north and south, Beartooth pass to the east and Yellowstone to the west.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7 of 29 - South Dakota</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-7-of-29-south-dakota/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 04:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-7-of-29-south-dakota/</guid>
      <description>Decided to leave most of my gear and head to the Black Hills in South Dakota to see the Mt Rushmore and the Crazy Horse memorials.
The first looks much more impressive when you are actully there. The second will be even more impressive once its finished &amp;hellip; the bus guide estimated that will happen in the next 20 - 30 years.
      Bikers on road near Rushmore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 of 29 - The prairies</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-6-of-29-the-prairies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 02:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-6-of-29-the-prairies/</guid>
      <description>Left Bismark in some rain and rejoined the Interstate 94, but not for long. Turned south and followed the Missouri river until entered the Standing Rock indian reservation. Soon after I entered South Dakota. You should the countryside. Nothing specific to see but a lot of it and scenery was spectacular in its vastness. The scenes from North by northwest sorung to mind as I was driving. Even got a little fed up with all the driving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 of 29 - Cold and hot</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-5-of-29-cold-and-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 13:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-5-of-29-cold-and-hot/</guid>
      <description>Met some nice people over breakfast and chatted for a while. One of the ladies works as a teacher at the local reservation. Told me a scary and dad story about a little boy who was fishing in a river in the south part of the US and somebody saw the boy behaving strangely as if dizzy. The boy complained the worms were biting him. Turns out the boy thought he was picking up worms to use as bait but they were in fact baby copperhead snakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 of 29 - Just the Interstate 94</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-4-of-29-just-the-interstate-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 01:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-4-of-29-just-the-interstate-94/</guid>
      <description>Not a very nice start to the day. Started raining early in the morning and so I had to pack a wet tent and everything that goes with it. The wetness just seems to impregnate everything else.
Hit the road at about 7am and it was still raining then but it did soon stop. Just as I thought everything was just find I noticed something dangling from one of the bags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 of 29 - Hitting the road</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-3-of-29-hitting-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 01:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-3-of-29-hitting-the-road/</guid>
      <description>Last night had a few loose nerves to which those close to me can attest. Got a little worried the Heritage wont be able to take all the luggage I had for it. Turns out it was fine and this photo confirms that.
  Fully loaded and ready to go. Possibly regretting taking to much stuff
  About an hour or so into my driving noticed that part of the luggage was listing to the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 of 29 - Got the bike</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-2-of-29-got-the-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 02:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-2-of-29-got-the-bike/</guid>
      <description>Outside Countryside Harley Davidson
  Not a very good start - lots of rain. Got picked-up in the morning and met this interesting guy who was doing the driving. My arrival at Countryside Harley Davidson was followed by the various paperwork and then it was time to meet the bike. The Electra glide was my second choice and the Heritage Softail Classic my first and the Heritage was what I got.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 of 29 - Flying there (for a long time)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 23:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</guid>
      <description>Inside the airplane
  First item on the menu is an apology. This was typed on my Samsung Galaxy phone and considering the quality of my usual typing on its virtual keyboard I think I will probably have some absolute spelling gems ;-)
12am We should have taken off at 11am but I am not really sure we did. The weather up here very sunny and best of all you guys in Pembrokeshire might have seen me as we flew over Fishguard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 of 29 - Flying there (for a long time)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 23:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</guid>
      <description>Inside the airplane
  First item on the menu is an apology. This was typed on my Samsung Galaxy phone and considering the quality of my usual typing on its virtual keyboard I think I will probably have some absolute spelling gems ;-)
12am We should have taken off at 11am but I am not really sure we did. The weather up here very sunny and best of all you guys in Pembrokeshire might have seen me as we flew over Fishguard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre US-trip motorcycle warm-up</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/pre-us-trip-motorcycle-warm-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 18:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/pre-us-trip-motorcycle-warm-up/</guid>
      <description>As my riding skills might be a little rusty before my US bike trip in June I decided to get a motorcycle for a few days and travel to Pembrokeshire and back. Started off in Manchester on Saturday morning and took the M56 towards northern Wales.
Great journey but very exhausting at took me much longer than it does in the car, I had to do quite a few stops on the way, on one of them even got to help a fellow French biker near Ruthin who was trying to get to Anglesey .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparations for my bike trip to the USA</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/preparations-for-my-bike-trip-to-the-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 19:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/preparations-for-my-bike-trip-to-the-usa/</guid>
      <description>Harley Davidson Heritage Softail Classic
  This has been a little wish of mine for ages and now that I (seem to) have the money and the time I have decided to go for it. My mental plans started about a year ago when I realised I really needed to pass my motorcycle test n the UK. Not a really silly thought. I met a guy in the lake district, when I was doing my 3-peak challenge, who told me that you could, for an extra fee, just drive in the States on a car driving licence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haverfordwest drivers beware! Well, sort of :-)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/haverfordwest-drivers-beware-well-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 21:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/haverfordwest-drivers-beware-well-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>This is supposed to be a joke but it does depend on how you look at it. It is because on Monday, April 16th, I did my CBT - Compulsory Basic Training for driving a motorcycle and at the end of the training - about 4pm I was set loose on the streets of Haverfordwest.
I would like to apologize to everyone as I kept driving a little to slow or left you waiting because it took me longer than normal to clear a roundabout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
