<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Add new tag on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/add-new-tag/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Add new tag on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 21:01:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/add-new-tag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stranded sheep in the Blue Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 21:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>The Sunday between Christmas and the New Year I spent hiking around Pembrokeshire and this time I went for walk no. 12 (Around Ynys Barry) taken from the book mentioned in some of my previous posts There is a local attraction called the Blue Lagoon that is just a few minutes away from the Aber Eiddy (also known as Abereiddy) car park where the walk originates from. The lagoon is actually an old man-made slate mining pit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pembrokeshire snow in January 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</guid>
      <description>Had a big snowstorm last night that covered Pembrokeshire with a bit of snow. These photos taken from a hike up to the highest peak in the Preseli hills - Foel Cwmcerwyn . Very windy at the top!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubijanje v imenu Faktorja X</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ubijanje-v-imenu-faktorja-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 09:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ubijanje-v-imenu-faktorja-x/</guid>
      <description>V Veliki Britaniji že nekaj Božičev zaporedno prihaja na britanski glasbeni lestvici do nadvlade pocukranih komadov iz tovarne pocukranih komadov Simona Cowell-a in njegovega X Factor glasbenega show-a.
Tudi za letošnji Božič je kazalo, da bo zopet zmagal njegov protežiranec in zmagovalec Faktorja X - letos je to uspelo Joe McElderry-u. Račune mu je prekrižala zelo odmevna Facebook kampanija Jona in Tracy Morter, imenovana Rage Against The Machine For Christmas No.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
