<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slovenia on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/slovenia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slovenia on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 19:00:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/slovenia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Savica falls and Lake Bohinj</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-savica-falls-and-lake-bohinj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 19:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-savica-falls-and-lake-bohinj/</guid>
      <description>This is an old favourite of mine and apparently for many Brits as well as during my short visit there saw countless UK reg cars on the roads.
The Savica waterfall is part of the Sava Bohinjka river which is joined by the Sava Dolinka near Radovljica to form the Sava river . That in turns flows into the Danube at Belgrade which discharges into the Black Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking the hills of Snowdon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 09:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I moved to Wales 2 years ago I had a quiet wish to climb the highest peak in this country - Snowdon. Last weekend was showing to be a perfect opportunity to fulfil that wish. I was working only till 12 pm and the forecast was for sunshine and high temperatures stretching way into the following week. Getting some good literature , so you know what your are doing, is very advisable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Treffgarne Mountain</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</guid>
      <description>This walk seemed the muddiest of them all, in fact I am wandering how exactly to wash my walking shoes and the washing machine is getting to be the favourite. This is the walk no. 32 and can easily be combined with no. 33 (Treffgarne Gorge) as they both start from the same point. That was actually my plan but my walking shoes got filled with lots of lovely mud hindering any furter hikes that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Queen to visit Slovenia</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</guid>
      <description>I was very surprised to hear that the British Queen Elisabeth II . is to visit Slovenia soon.
 Buckingham Palace press releases
ANNOUNCEMENT OF STATE VISITS TO SLOVENIA AND SLOVAKIA
26 June 2008
THE FOLLOWING STATEMENT IS ISSUED BY THE PRESS SECRETARY TO THE QUEEN
 T&amp;gt; he Queen and The Duke of Edinburgh will pay State Visits to: Slovenia, at the invitation of President Dr Danilo Tuerk ; and Slovakia , at the invitation of President Ivan Gasparovic , during this Autumn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No smoking, please</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</guid>
      <description>I see that Slovenia is quite behind the smoking ban that is in the process of being inforced across the EU . I arrived in Wales on the 7th of April and that was the weekend, when the ban started here . There was no big deal, however we will see what will happen in a few months time when the temperature drops. The ban was enforced just before the summer and it was followed by a very warm period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
