<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorised on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/uncategorised/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorised on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:00:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/uncategorised/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spending a day at a Birmingham police station</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/spending-a-day-at-a-birmingham-police-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/spending-a-day-at-a-birmingham-police-station/</guid>
      <description>Not often would I brag about spending almost the entire day in the company of the police. Lets face it, you usually have to deal with them if you have done something wrong or something wrong has been done to you and nobody I know really wants that.
But I think it was all for a common good today. A large group of mostly police volunteers organise workshops and observed ride-outs under the scheme called Bike Safe .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Debela Peč, 1,014m</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-debela-pec-1014m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 19:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-debela-pec-1014m/</guid>
      <description>A great hike up a stunning mountain. The drive to the small carpark in the middle of nowhere is an experience in itself. Then you set off up a disused track and end up in a large open area called Klek plateau.
This is where the tricky part comes in, the most difficult part of the trip is the navigation. Trying to find the exit point to the path continuing towards the peaks of Debela Pec and Lipanca.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little boat trip</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-little-boat-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 21:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-little-boat-trip/</guid>
      <description>Went on a little boat trip with some friends on the Cleddau river in Pembrokeshire. They even served us fish &amp;amp; chips and beer and wine. Very cool.
    The skipper awaits
          </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
