<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Florida on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/florida/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Florida on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:14:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/florida/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</guid>
      <description>I have now managed to send off the container to the manufacturer Aerodyne in Florida . I have just driven back from Swansea where I send off the container through a DHL ServicePoint location in the Parc Tawe Staples shop. Great service, if you ask me, as you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay a high price to have your packed shipped and you also choose what boy its going to be sent in - the price of shipment depends on the size of the box, but with a upper weight limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 19:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</guid>
      <description>My recent visit to the motherland gave me the opportunity for yet another skydiving session, I joined my instructor and mentor Aleš Debeljak from the Paranoia skydiving school.
All went well and on the third jump of the second day just as I exited the Cessna 206 I apparently managed to hook my rig on the side of the door which resulted in a nasty tear in my container on the reserve parachute flap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sands of speed</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 16:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</guid>
      <description>This is the name of a 7 mile (11 km) stretch of sandy beach located on the south Wales coastline between Tenby and Swansea . The most impressive feature of this beach is its flatness and straightness at such a long length. You can see the satellite view below.
In the early 20th century the sands were often used as a racing course and later, in the 1920s, it was used for land speed records .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
