<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>England on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/england/</link>
    <description>Recent content in England on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 19:33:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/england/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 4 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-4-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 19:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-4-of-4/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1453&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;720&amp;rdquo;]   A shark in the big tank in the London Aquarium[/caption]
Not feeling very well in the morning of the last day, this cold has been getting the better of me and running around London does not help it getting any better. Drugging-up with anti-inflammatories not helped either.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1454&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;225&amp;rdquo;]   The London Eye - close to the top[/caption]
First port of call was the London eye I booked the previous day on-line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmap-ing me</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/schmaping-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 19:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/schmaping-me/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_639&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;]   The photo of Bristol Cathedral chosen for the fifth edition of the Schmap Bristol Guide[/caption]
I received a mail today from an on-line publisher of digital travel guides called Schmap that my photo of Bristol Cathedral was chosen to be included in the fifth edition of the Schmap Bristol Guide .
I received an e-mail a while ago saying that the photo was short-listed for it and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think my photos were good enough for somebody to publish them in a guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No smoking, please</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</guid>
      <description>I see that Slovenia is quite behind the smoking ban that is in the process of being inforced across the EU . I arrived in Wales on the 7th of April and that was the weekend, when the ban started here . There was no big deal, however we will see what will happen in a few months time when the temperature drops. The ban was enforced just before the summer and it was followed by a very warm period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
