<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Broken foot</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2021/broken-foot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2021/broken-foot/</guid>
      <description>I have done a few things in my life and and a lot of them involving my feet: I&amp;rsquo;ve hiked for hundreds of miles round Pembrokeshire, jumped out of an airplane 146 times, hiked up Kilimanjaro and the worse injury I had was a sore heel.
But hell noooo, I have a lovely afternoon stroll on a gravel road and I go and break a foot. That&amp;rsquo;s it, my first fractured bone in my life at 48.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pablo</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2021/2021-05-21-pablo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 15:19:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2021/2021-05-21-pablo/</guid>
      <description>Had a call about a possible adder attack on a family cat and the owner brought down the cat and also the adder. He was brought in a small detergent box. After carefully opening the box and tipping the snake into a large plastic container we realised we were dealing with a grass snake, most likley male. These snakes are non-venomous and do not constrict so they are absolutely harmless to people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 15: Going Home (Day 8 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-15-going-home-day-8-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 19:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-15-going-home-day-8-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, October 5th Didn&amp;rsquo;t have much time to savour the moment. In the evening we had our certificates and our beers and warm meals and a shower. Up at stupid o&amp;rsquo;clock to get to the Kilimanjaro Int&amp;rsquo;l airport that was about 1.5-2 hours away.
When we got there and when I tried to get into the airport the security guard started to say that my passport was fake. FAKE!! It must have been a bit of travel drowsiness and it being very very early in the morning but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t comprehend what was going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 14: The Descent (Day 7 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-14-descent-day-7-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 19:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-14-descent-day-7-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Friday, October 4th The descent from Kili was done very quickly. Not sure if the guides were worried I might not make it down but two of them grabbed me by my arms and almost carried me downhill. When we got back to the base camp at Kibo we were given about an hour to rest and have a warm meal. After that we had to pack all our stuff and head to Horombo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 13: Uhuru Peak / Horombo Hut (Day 6 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-13-kibo-hut-uhuru-peak-day-6-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 19:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-13-kibo-hut-uhuru-peak-day-6-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, 3 October Elevation: 5,895 m (Uhuru peak), alpine desert
This post was written months after I actually did the climb. There were so many emotions surrounding this day I needed time to process them. So as I procrastinated the post I ended just forgetting about it. Putting it to words and posting it onto this blog was of secondary importance to me. The thoughts and memories will be mine forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12: Kibo Hut / Uhuru Peak (Day 5 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-12-kibo-hut-uhuru-peak-day-5-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 19:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-12-kibo-hut-uhuru-peak-day-5-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday, 2 October Elevation: 4,703 m (Kibo Hut), alpine desert
Today&amp;rsquo;s hike was supposed to be 5h long to the Marangu route&amp;rsquo;s basecamp at Kibo hut. Somewhere along the 11 kilometres we hiked we left the marshland and entered what could be best described as rocky desert, a lunar landscape that has been plonked down on top of an African mountain.
  This is also where some in the group started to feel the altitude problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11: Horombo Huts and Mawenzi (Day 4 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-11-horombo-huts-and-mawenzi-day-4-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 19:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-11-horombo-huts-and-mawenzi-day-4-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, 1 October Elevation: 2,700 m (Horombo Hut) / 4310 m (Mawenzi Hut), moorland / alpine terrain
A slightly different day today. Planned to be an acclimatisation day but difficult to acclimatise at 2,700 metres. Didn&amp;rsquo;t really seem high enough. None of us had any sorts of problems even at the upper end of the hike just above Zebra rocks. The interesting bit was the snow storm we hiked through. And this is when we had a lovely sunny morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10: Horombo Hut (Day 3 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-10-horombo-hut-day-3-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 19:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-10-horombo-hut-day-3-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Monday, 30 September Elevation: 3,720 m, moorland terrain
Spirits very high we started our mountain hut routine. Woken up by one of the porter for coffee and tea and then the &amp;ldquo;wishy washy&amp;rdquo; was brought which was basically a small bucket of warm water each and some soap. This was the same in the evenings and allowed us a little bit of hygiene. This bit of &amp;ldquo;luxury&amp;rdquo; was omitted at the highest - Kibo hut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9: Mandara Hut (Day 2 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-9-mandara-hut-day-2-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 19:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-9-mandara-hut-day-2-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, 29 September Elevation: 2,700 m, forest terrain
We had a quick meeting at reception and we were given water, we also gave the 9kg luggage to the porters by putting them in special numbered green bags. I had one numbered no. 10 and it was &amp;ldquo;mine&amp;rdquo; for the rest of the trip. I would always have the same porter, his name was Jaffa and I think he also carried another hiker&amp;rsquo;s green bag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8: Marangu (Day 1 of Kilimanjaro part)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-8-marangu-day-1-of-kilimanjaro-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 19:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-8-marangu-day-1-of-kilimanjaro-part/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, 28 September Elevation: 1,860 m, forest terrain (Marangu gate)
Leaving Mto Wan Mbu and hitting the road, dropped off a group at Arusha airport and some us at a hotel in Arusha. The rest heading towards Nairobi.
Had a weird interaction with the driver who when we asked him for a toilet stop dismissed the option flat out. We were taken aback a little but he soon realised that this might not be the right course of action and stopped at a petrol station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7: Ngorongoro Crater / Mto Wa Mbu</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-7-ngorongoro-crater-mto-wa-mbu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-7-ngorongoro-crater-mto-wa-mbu/</guid>
      <description>Friday, 27 September Just woke up going to the loo only to realise there is a large herd of zebras right besides the tents. I pitched up on the outside edge of the other tents so at one point they were only a metre or so away.
  Today we changed vehicles and switched to 4x4 Toyota Land cruisers. We had 4 but one of them had a problem so their passengers had to get into the other three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6: Ngorongoro Crater</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-6-ngorongoro-crater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 13:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-6-ngorongoro-crater/</guid>
      <description>Thursday, 26 September Another interesting night in regards to the local wildlife but this time we knew what to expect. Again hienas trashed our rubbish bins, one of or fellow hikers got kinda chased round the toilet block by a hiena. It might have happened slightly differently but this is how I&amp;rsquo;m serving it and I suggest you believe it. 😉 Also the lion roars and zebras giving out weird sounds were the repeat repertoire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5: Serengeti National Park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-5-serengeti-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 17:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-5-serengeti-national-park/</guid>
      <description>Wednesday, 25 September What a night! Sleeping in the tent and surrounded by sounds of the Serengeti wildlife. At one point I had a zebra come right close to the tent. It must have been just 10 feet or so away. Then the there was a constant vocalising of the hienas who actually had a field day on the bin belonging to the other group that was in the same campsite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4: Serengeti National Park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-4-serengeti-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 06:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-4-serengeti-national-park/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday, 24 September Still being under the impression of the stunning sunset over lake Victoria the night before, we started again with an early breakfast and a couple of quick stops in town to get more supplies. We also managed to source some ice that we put in a chiller box with all our beers.
The road took us slightly south towards Seronera. We then made a right into the western entrance to the Serengeti national park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: Lake Victoria</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-3-lake-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 18:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-3-lake-victoria/</guid>
      <description>Monday, 23 September Had some technical problems with the truck last night. Just as we were getting to the resort there was a loud bang under the truck and seems it was some sort of suspension issue. They had parts in Nairobi that two guys had to get to us and the only way was by road. They were working on the repairs most of the night.
  Got the truck sorted out but we were about 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Kisii</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-2-kisii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 18:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-2-kisii/</guid>
      <description>Sunday, September 22nd Started the day really early. I think I set my alarm to 4:15am. Which is basically 2:15am on my internal British clock. We had some breakfast in the hotel and packed our stuff in the bus, which is actually a modified truck.
  We headed out of Nairobi and towards Kisii. It&amp;rsquo;s a long drive. About 8 to 9h as the itinerary warned but we did stop a few times which helped break up the otherwise arduous journey quite a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: Nairobi</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-1-nairobi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 17:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/day-1-nairobi/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, September 21st Started the day in the skies above Africa. A long 8.5h flight to Nairobi from London. Not a wink of sleep.
Clearing immigration was actually a breeze with the E-Visa which is basically a visa you get online before you travel. However it&amp;rsquo;s still quite weird they take your photo and fingerprints from BOTH hands. I had a private transfer from the airport to the hotel courtesy of the company that is organising the trip - Intrepid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Itinerary</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/itinerary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 07:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/itinerary/</guid>
      <description>So the plan is to go by car to Heathrow T4, catch a light to Nairobi, Kenya. I am supposed to get a shuttle from the airport from the airport to a hotel in downtown Nairobi. The group I am travelling with have a meeting the following day in the same hotel.
The day after we get on a private bus aka &amp;ldquo;safari truck&amp;rdquo; and go towards Kisii . We are supposed to arrive there about 9h later!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spending a day at a Birmingham police station</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/spending-a-day-at-a-birmingham-police-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/spending-a-day-at-a-birmingham-police-station/</guid>
      <description>Not often would I brag about spending almost the entire day in the company of the police. Lets face it, you usually have to deal with them if you have done something wrong or something wrong has been done to you and nobody I know really wants that.
But I think it was all for a common good today. A large group of mostly police volunteers organise workshops and observed ride-outs under the scheme called Bike Safe .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brecon beacons: Cribyn - Pen-y-fan - Corn Du</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/brecon-beacons-cribyn-pen-y-fan-corn-du/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 21:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/brecon-beacons-cribyn-pen-y-fan-corn-du/</guid>
      <description>Modified the usual hike that goes straight up from the Cwm Gwdi carpark. Elevation gain 914 m.
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel vaccinations</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/travel-vaccinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/travel-vaccinations/</guid>
      <description>One of the matters you need to address when traveling to many countries in Africa are health orientated. The company Intrepid who I am using for the trip does mention this n their travel advice and probably the best place to go for more advice is your GP or a travel vaccination centre. There are a couple of very good websites that will help with that.
https://travelhealthpro.org.uk/ and https://www.fitfortravel.nhs.uk/ There are quite a few diseases that are mentioned for my trip that includes two countries: Kenya and Tanzania so I need to be covered for both.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Viševnik, 2,050m</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-visevnik-2050m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 19:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-visevnik-2050m/</guid>
      <description>An old favourite. Have been up it only twice before as far as I can remember. The last time it was a scorching hot summers day and this is also when I learned about dogs and how peculiar they can be be.
I took our family dog with me and to make sure we were both hydrated I took a bottle of water for her and a bottle of flavoured water for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Krim 1,107m</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-krim-1107m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-krim-1107m/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps not as prominent of a mountain as the other ones you could climb in the alps but a good training ground. Funny enough quite comparable to the Snowdon hike. Krim is 1,107 metres tall and you start the hike from Iški Vintgar at 420m so a height climb of about 750m. The climb from Pen-y-pass (559 m) to Snowdon (1,085 m) is about 526 metres or 817 metres if you start from Llyn Gwynant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Debela Peč, 1,014m</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-debela-pec-1014m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 19:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-debela-pec-1014m/</guid>
      <description>A great hike up a stunning mountain. The drive to the small carpark in the middle of nowhere is an experience in itself. Then you set off up a disused track and end up in a large open area called Klek plateau.
This is where the tricky part comes in, the most difficult part of the trip is the navigation. Trying to find the exit point to the path continuing towards the peaks of Debela Pec and Lipanca.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puncture prevented further training</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/puncture-prevented-further-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 19:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/puncture-prevented-further-training/</guid>
      <description>I had a bit of an eventful day today. Set of to hike up Pen y fan , had to find a way out of town as there were was a road closure and ended up going a way I don&amp;rsquo;t usually use. Somewhere on that trip I must have ridden over something sharp. By the time I got to Leominster about 20 minutes away I felt the bike being unstable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for new boots</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/time-for-new-boots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 19:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/time-for-new-boots/</guid>
      <description>I had to bite the bullet and try finding some good boots that will last me for the training I have to do plus be suitable for the Kilimanjaro trip, so hot savannah and ice cold Uhuru peak.
   I knew I was going to need some help and I was dreading having to go to one of the big corps and one of their outlets. I needed some proper help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The full Malverns, up and down</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/the-full-malverns-up-and-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 19:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/the-full-malverns-up-and-down/</guid>
      <description>I finally made it. Hiked all the way up the Malverns and then back again. A total of about 30 km in 6 hours, 45 minutes. Doing these distances does help build up the stamina for the uphill parts of the Kilimanjaro route. However should not neglect the final day when we will descend the mountain where we will do about 20 km which should take us 5-6 hours.
  However am taking quite a beating on my feet, something not completely right with my old hiking boots, a pair of Salomon X Ultra 3 Mid GTX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another training day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/another-training-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 18:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/another-training-day/</guid>
      <description>A glorious sunny Saturday on the May Bank holiday weekend.
This time I started at the southern end at Chase End and worked my way north. Was able to reach Upper Wyche. Still have not reached the goal of doing the whole Malvern Hills up and down (or the other way for that matter).
The hills especially round the southern part of the Malverns were covered in violet, all down to the abundance of bluebells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hike up Pen-y-fan</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/a-hike-up-pen-y-fan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 19:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/a-hike-up-pen-y-fan/</guid>
      <description>A training hike up Pen-y-fan on a Easter weekend.
            </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing Mount Kilimanjaro - The start of the adventure</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/climbing-mount-kilimanjaro-the-start-of-the-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 20:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/climbing-mount-kilimanjaro-the-start-of-the-adventure/</guid>
      <description>Image by Greg Montani from Pixabay In this case with booking. I heard of a friend using the company Intrepid Travel several years ago when she went on a fabulous trip to south America.
Have been itching to do something myself and a few weeks ago saw in idea about climbing Mt Kilimanjaro. At 5,895 metres its not an easy endeavour, certainly the highest and the longest I have ever hiked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia, December 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/slovenia-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 14:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/slovenia-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>    Some more musically inspired Christmas decorations on Levstik square
          The &amp;#39;flancat&amp;#39; pastry and hot sweet herbal tea
    People in the UK won&amp;#39;t really know about the sport performed here
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great evening autumnal joyride near Brockhampton and the river Wye</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/a-great-evening-autumnal-joyride-near-brockhampton-and-the-river-wye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/a-great-evening-autumnal-joyride-near-brockhampton-and-the-river-wye/</guid>
      <description>Moving to Herefordshire was one of the more challenging things to do but its lovely to see how beautiful the countryside can be.
  All Saints’ Church, Brockhampton
            Near Bromyard
    Malvern Hills, Ragged Stone
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lawrenny and Creswell Quay</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/lawrenny-and-creswell-quay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 13:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/lawrenny-and-creswell-quay/</guid>
      <description>              Lawrenny woods
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A visit to Slovenia, October 2017</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-visit-to-slovenia-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 07:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-visit-to-slovenia-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t been here for 10 months and have missed the place. Just look at the views.
            </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP Dad</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/rip-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 19:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/rip-dad/</guid>
      <description>Robert Joseph McDowell
  Robert Joseph McDowell
November 4th 1938 - April 29th 2017
RIP Dad
son, Martin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tŷ Canol nature reserve, Pentre Ifan and the original site of the Stonehenge bluestones</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/ty-canol-nature-reserve-pentre-ifan-and-the-original-site-of-the-stonehenge-bluestones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 21:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/ty-canol-nature-reserve-pentre-ifan-and-the-original-site-of-the-stonehenge-bluestones/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t been on this little gem for a few years now. Some parts can be quite muddy but everything is repaid with the views of the enchanted forest that is the Tŷ Canol nature reserve. So amazing. The photos don&amp;rsquo;t do it justice.
This walk was a modification of the Pentre Ifan walk from circular Pembrokeshire walks book by Dennis and Jan Kelsall. Only this time I extended it from the Pentre Ifan burial chamber towards the now confirmed site where the Stonehenge bluestones were sourced from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little boat trip</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-little-boat-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 21:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-little-boat-trip/</guid>
      <description>Went on a little boat trip with some friends on the Cleddau river in Pembrokeshire. They even served us fish &amp;amp; chips and beer and wine. Very cool.
    The skipper awaits
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bohinj still rocks in the winter</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/bohinj-still-rocks-in-the-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 21:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/bohinj-still-rocks-in-the-winter/</guid>
      <description>An all time favourite hiking destination.
  Church of St. John the Baptist in Ribčev Laz
    Vrh nad Želimljami
    Vrh nad Želimljami
    View of Triglav from my easyJet flight back to London Stansted
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladyclough woods, Ashop valley and Stanage Edge</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/ladyclough-woods-ashop-valley-and-stanage-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 18:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/ladyclough-woods-ashop-valley-and-stanage-edge/</guid>
      <description>A nice little tour of the Peak District.
  Ashop valley
    Ladyclough woods
    Ladyclough woods
    Ladyclough woods
    Ladyclough woods
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberglasney Garden</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/aberglasney-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 07:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/aberglasney-garden/</guid>
      <description>This lovely estate is about 20 away from Carmarthen on the road to Llandeilo.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uber blunder in Essex</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/uber-blunder-in-essex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/uber-blunder-in-essex/</guid>
      <description>Bit the bullet and ordered my first Uber ride in November 2014 when I was in London. It went very well but it was for a very short trip.
The second one was in April 2015 and it was from stansted airport to a nearby b&amp;amp;b about 15 minutes away. I loved the fact that you know beforehand who will be picking you up, what the reg number of the car is and where the car is on a map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carriacou - the island surrounded by reefs</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/carriacou-the-island-surrounded-by-reefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 14:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/carriacou-the-island-surrounded-by-reefs/</guid>
      <description>View of Hillsborough from the hospital in Belair
  There are two public routes on and off the island. The Osprey ferry and the SVG flight. Now it seems to be an established fact that the ferry is a much more adventurous route meaning it is often a nausea inducing experience even for the more seasoned sea travellers. Anecdotally the trip to Carriacou is usually worse than the trip back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appeal for donations for Carriacou Animal Hospital</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/appeal-for-donations-for-carriacou-animal-hospital/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 17:11:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/appeal-for-donations-for-carriacou-animal-hospital/</guid>
      <description>Photo by CAH
  What a great experience. Lots of memories and and a moderate skin tan that will disappear quite quickly in this Welsh winter.
Although there were a lot of nice relaxing moments on the beach there were also lots of animal care that we were involved with. The beautiful scenery of the island should not conceal the tremendous work Kathy, Shurlyn and all the people that are involved and help out with the Carriacou Animal Hospital (CAH).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First impressions</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 01:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Writing this at least a couple of days into my stay. The passport control people nearly didn&amp;rsquo;t let me in the country as they seem to pretend they didn&amp;rsquo;t know about Carriacou animal hospital and to top it off the donated medical supplies got seized by customs. With the great effort from Penny in Grenada we managed to get them back the following day which meant I missed the morning ferry to Carriacou.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting off</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/setting-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 23:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/setting-off/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t think I have ever travelled with so much luggage. Besides my own stuff I will also bring over some consumables like surgical gloves, flea treatment and so on. Got some great plastic containers that are nice and waterproof.
  View of the airplane
  Those 4 boxes above was how I got everything from the WVS. I was a little worried about how I am going to get all the luggage from the long term car park, on the bus and then on the terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chikungunya what? Is that a local chicken dish?</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/chikungunya-what-is-that-a-local-chicken-dish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 16:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/chikungunya-what-is-that-a-local-chicken-dish/</guid>
      <description>The Chikungunya virus / Sun, Siyang et al., 2013
  Soon after starting planning my volunteer trip to Carriacou I was given advice about vaccinations I would require. These were basically for rabies and tetanus. As I was tested and proven that I already had enough anti-bodies against tetanus (Clostridium tetani) all I had to do was to get my rabies shots. Great. Cashed out over £110 for this and thought this was it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering for the Worldwide Veterinary Service on the island of Carriacou</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/volunteering-for-the-worldwide-veterinary-service-on-the-island-of-carriacou/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 09:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/carriacou-2015/volunteering-for-the-worldwide-veterinary-service-on-the-island-of-carriacou/</guid>
      <description>After months of preparation I will finally been taking a trip to the Caribbean island of Carriacou to do a few weeks of volunteer work for the Carriacou Animal Hospital (Facebook page ). The trip was coordinated in conjunction with the WVS (Worldwide Veterinary Service) who has offered me loads of support and guidance.
I have put over £1,000 towards the trip but the CAH, WVS and I are also looking for any charitable donations of veterinary medical supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luggage FUBAR riding a motorcycle</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2014/luggage-fubar-riding-a-motorcycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 17:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2014/luggage-fubar-riding-a-motorcycle/</guid>
      <description>Had a great trip to the Algarve recently and rented a Honda Shadow motorcycle for a week. On one of the last few days of my stay there I planned a trip to the south-western tip of Portugal - Cabo de São Vicente and Sagres. However all did not go well from my start in Albufeira. As I knew I was going to be on the road for at least an hour, perhaps 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo uses the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;

 &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/pkg/html/template/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;html/template&lt;/a&gt;

 library for
its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very
small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of
logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other
template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of
similarities in Go templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another energy provider</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/yet-another-energy-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 10:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/yet-another-energy-provider/</guid>
      <description>I have lived at my current address for last 6 years and started of using Swalec as my electricity and gas provider. Then found out they were ripping me off so I switched &amp;hellip; only after I clawed back the money they owed me. Switched to EDF which had its own little scams. They failed to clearly explain that they will be increasing my bills by switching me to a Standard tariff if I used their smart meter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riding the Honda GL1800 Goldwing</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/riding-the-honda-gl1800-goldwing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2013 08:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/riding-the-honda-gl1800-goldwing/</guid>
      <description>As the year has been coming to an end and winter seems just round the corner I decided to fill some of my inter-locuming days with a bit of biking. Hired a bike but this time something a little more comfy for the longer journeys - a proper touring bike with heated arm rests and seats would you believe it!! This time I rented a touring bike from the same Manchester rental company I used before .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter warmth by croud sourcing</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/winter-warmth-by-croud-sourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 19:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/winter-warmth-by-croud-sourcing/</guid>
      <description>One thing to note to anyone attempting to hike up the Snežnik mountain is that the place is quite remote. If you set off from Ljubljana the road takes you past Postojna and towards Croatia and you then have to drive on a gravel road for quite some time to get to the Sviščaki village. From there the route takes you through a beautiful bear country forest.
About half an hour or so from the summit I walked onto this clearing where there was a lot of chopped wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dodging storm clouds</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/dodging-storm-clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/dodging-storm-clouds/</guid>
      <description>I guess a lot of seasoned bikers are familiar this skill but I had to develop olit completely from scratch and it was up to necessity rather than fancying myself taking on a skill I might not use ever again.
During my few weeks biking in the US this June I got quite good at it. What it basically is that as a motorcyclist you try avoiding getting wet by avoiding rainy clouds as they intercept your route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krim</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/krim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 19:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/krim/</guid>
      <description>If Krim is covered with clouds in the evening then there will be bad weather tomorrow. If its not then the weather will be fair.
 Well, that what we were told and that is the knowledge we stuck by.
Krim is a 1,107m tall mountain on the southern outskirts of the Ljubljana moors. In all the years I have lived in Slovenia I have never actually been up it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avenue of the Giants</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/avenue-of-the-giants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 17:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/avenue-of-the-giants/</guid>
      <description>The name sounds like something from a children&amp;rsquo;s adventure book, perhaps depicting an overgrown legume, but this was an actually road-sign I saw in northern California that was inviting me to leave the route 101 and explore its mysteries.
This is actually the name of a byway, a road that runs close to the Route 101 but is much MUCH nicer. The roads twists and rolls round enormous Redwood trees, which are really sequoia trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My biking retrospective</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/my-biking-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 20:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/my-biking-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>End of the trip in Chicago, Illinois
Today marked the first week since I hit the road. It seems like ages since I departed Chicago and I must say the trip has given me the desired effect and changed my perspective on biking and bikers. Long I thought them to be criminal gang associated thugs. But the truth really is far faaar from that misconception. They are a really friendly bunch of people that will always help each-other in trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of the road</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-end-of-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 20:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-end-of-the-road/</guid>
      <description>Distance travelled: ~8,000 miles (just under 13,000 km)
The 17 states that I had a chance to see:
 Illinois Milwaukee (briefly) Minessota (briefly) North Dakota South Dakota Wyoming Montana Idaho (briefly) Washington Oregon California Nevada Arizona Utah Colorado (briefly) Nebraska (briefly) Iowa (briefly)  People met: loads
Technical issues with the motorcycle: almost none, substantial oil addition in Utah at about 6.125 miles into trip. When I wrote this article I seemed to have completely forgotten about my problem getting the bike started on Day 1, when I was still on the Eaglerider carpark in Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 19:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/chicago/</guid>
      <description>Chicago river from Lower North Lakeshore drive
Drove from Morris, Illinois in the morning straight downtown. Although sometimes glitchy the built-in Android turn-by-turn satnav saved the day by giving me good verbal instructions to guide me to the Monaco hotel where I stayed until my flight on Tuesday. Left most of the luggage there and then drove to the Eaglerider shop at the Chicago, Countryside Harley-Davidson branch. Very thrilling ride but not that difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quick run towards Chicago</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-quick-run-towards-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-quick-run-towards-chicago/</guid>
      <description>After completing my wish of seeing the Grand Canyon I realized I need to start towards Chicago. The day before sort of already was a travel east but it was more south-east than northeast which it should have been. I started from the Colorado town of Grand Junction . The previous day travel was not pleasant at all. More like excruciatingly hot. It felt like I was in a stove and the air just kept getting hotter and there was no way of getting out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/grand-canyon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 02:38:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/grand-canyon/</guid>
      <description>And this was the penultimate final destination on my trip. Amaaaazing and truly awe inspiring. Those who have seen it probably know what I mean. Just the size of the whole landscape really gets you.
I was really on my way to Chicago but after sleeping on my thoughts when I was in St. George in Utah I decided to give it a go. I was going to go to the horseshoe but the local road was closed for roadworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death Valley, Las Vegas and the Hoover dam - 4 states in one day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/death-valley-las-vegas-and-the-hoover-dam-4-states-in-one-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 04:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/death-valley-las-vegas-and-the-hoover-dam-4-states-in-one-day/</guid>
      <description>Road down Deat Valley
Decided to give it a go and hope it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bite me in the backside if I turn out to be late for my bike drop-off on Saturday I. Chicago. I decided I really wanted to see at least some of Grand Canyon and I went for it. From Bishop in California I headed southeast towards Las Vegas by crossing the &amp;ldquo;infamous&amp;rdquo; Death Valley. In fact its not that scary and there is even a small basic petrol station and motel there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco and the Yosemite national park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/san-francisco-and-the-yosemite-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 05:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/san-francisco-and-the-yosemite-national-park/</guid>
      <description>Yosemite national park
  I put these two together as I visited them on the same day. They are only about 4 hours drive from each other. I started the day in Santa Rosa and headed down highway 101 that leads into San Francisco over the Golden Gate bridge. The bridge always used to be a toll one as I recall but now they have a silly electronic system where your plate is scanned and then your account gets charged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/oregon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/oregon/</guid>
      <description>Not one of the very impressive days on my trip. The weather precipitation radar was showing quite a lot of scattered activity in the whole northwestern quarter of Oregon. I did have a little wish to see Mount St. Helens where that big eruption happened in 1980. This would actually take me northeast to my then position in Vancouver (yes, there is one in the state of Washington. So this plan was scrapped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redwood forests of northern California</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/redwood-forests-of-northern-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 02:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/redwood-forests-of-northern-california/</guid>
      <description>So now I am in lala land. OK. A bit mean of me and certainly not fair to generalise a specific entertainment made in a particular part of Los Angeles to the whole state of California. So far the surroundings are mesmerising. Its like riding in a scene of Jurassic park. Not even sure why they didn&amp;rsquo;t film the outdoor scenes here. Come to think of it, where did they film those scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 05:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/seattle/</guid>
      <description>Travel by ferry to Port Townsend. Olympic mountains not as impressive as thought but to prove me wrong would take to much time. Also the weather got worse so I had to go to a hotel for the night. The camp in Port Angeles was not really tent friendly. No soil to talk off, just a few centimetres, the coming storm would have blown my tent far away. So decided to cut my stay in the area short and took the ferry from Bainbridge island to downtown Seattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier national park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/glacier-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 15:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/glacier-national-park/</guid>
      <description>The previous day saw me hit the road big time as I rode from Yellowstone right up to St. Mary&amp;rsquo;s - a little town on the eastern entrance to the Glacier NP. My plan was to drive up the Road to the Sun over Logan&amp;rsquo;s pass. Unfortunately the road was closed due to all the snow that had to be cleared only to then have to do roadworks it in the few months that were left to do it in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cascade mountains</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-cascade-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 15:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/the-cascade-mountains/</guid>
      <description>After staying in a great KOA campsite in Winthrop, Washington, I took the road across the Cascade mountains. The scenery was similar to the Going to the Sun road in Montana. Very stunning mountain scenery, lakes, waterfalls &amp;hellip; it had everything. Unfortunately i didn&amp;rsquo;t see any bears but I was told they are frequently seen on the road.
Stopped for a cup of coffee on the way and took the ferry crossing to Port Townsend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone national park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/yellowstone-national-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 13:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/yellowstone-national-park/</guid>
      <description>Day 8 was a travelling day from Rapid city, SD to Cody in Wyoming on the entrance to Yellowstone national park. Got lost a little in Worland and took an unwilling detour through a town called Thermopolis.
Didn&amp;rsquo;t find a suitable camp so I took a room in a motel. And just by chance I found this charming lodge called the Grizzly Lodge in a small town of Silver Gate. This town is somewhat in the middle of nowhere, tucked between the hills north and south, Beartooth pass to the east and Yellowstone to the west.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7 of 29 - South Dakota</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-7-of-29-south-dakota/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 04:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-7-of-29-south-dakota/</guid>
      <description>Decided to leave most of my gear and head to the Black Hills in South Dakota to see the Mt Rushmore and the Crazy Horse memorials.
The first looks much more impressive when you are actully there. The second will be even more impressive once its finished &amp;hellip; the bus guide estimated that will happen in the next 20 - 30 years.
      Bikers on road near Rushmore</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 of 29 - The prairies</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-6-of-29-the-prairies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 02:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-6-of-29-the-prairies/</guid>
      <description>Left Bismark in some rain and rejoined the Interstate 94, but not for long. Turned south and followed the Missouri river until entered the Standing Rock indian reservation. Soon after I entered South Dakota. You should the countryside. Nothing specific to see but a lot of it and scenery was spectacular in its vastness. The scenes from North by northwest sorung to mind as I was driving. Even got a little fed up with all the driving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 of 29 - Cold and hot</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-5-of-29-cold-and-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 13:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-5-of-29-cold-and-hot/</guid>
      <description>Met some nice people over breakfast and chatted for a while. One of the ladies works as a teacher at the local reservation. Told me a scary and dad story about a little boy who was fishing in a river in the south part of the US and somebody saw the boy behaving strangely as if dizzy. The boy complained the worms were biting him. Turns out the boy thought he was picking up worms to use as bait but they were in fact baby copperhead snakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 of 29 - Just the Interstate 94</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-4-of-29-just-the-interstate-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 01:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-4-of-29-just-the-interstate-94/</guid>
      <description>Not a very nice start to the day. Started raining early in the morning and so I had to pack a wet tent and everything that goes with it. The wetness just seems to impregnate everything else.
Hit the road at about 7am and it was still raining then but it did soon stop. Just as I thought everything was just find I noticed something dangling from one of the bags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 of 29 - Hitting the road</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-3-of-29-hitting-the-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 01:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-3-of-29-hitting-the-road/</guid>
      <description>Last night had a few loose nerves to which those close to me can attest. Got a little worried the Heritage wont be able to take all the luggage I had for it. Turns out it was fine and this photo confirms that.
  Fully loaded and ready to go. Possibly regretting taking to much stuff
  About an hour or so into my driving noticed that part of the luggage was listing to the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 of 29 - Got the bike</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-2-of-29-got-the-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 02:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-2-of-29-got-the-bike/</guid>
      <description>Outside Countryside Harley Davidson
  Not a very good start - lots of rain. Got picked-up in the morning and met this interesting guy who was doing the driving. My arrival at Countryside Harley Davidson was followed by the various paperwork and then it was time to meet the bike. The Electra glide was my second choice and the Heritage Softail Classic my first and the Heritage was what I got.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 of 29 - Flying there (for a long time)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 23:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</guid>
      <description>Inside the airplane
  First item on the menu is an apology. This was typed on my Samsung Galaxy phone and considering the quality of my usual typing on its virtual keyboard I think I will probably have some absolute spelling gems ;-)
12am We should have taken off at 11am but I am not really sure we did. The weather up here very sunny and best of all you guys in Pembrokeshire might have seen me as we flew over Fishguard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 of 29 - Flying there (for a long time)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 23:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/day-1-of-29-flying-there-for-a-long-time/</guid>
      <description>Inside the airplane
  First item on the menu is an apology. This was typed on my Samsung Galaxy phone and considering the quality of my usual typing on its virtual keyboard I think I will probably have some absolute spelling gems ;-)
12am We should have taken off at 11am but I am not really sure we did. The weather up here very sunny and best of all you guys in Pembrokeshire might have seen me as we flew over Fishguard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready to go...</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/almost-ready-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 08:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/almost-ready-to-go/</guid>
      <description>Taken on my recent trip to Wales
    Taken on my recent trip to Wales
    Taken on my recent trip to Wales, Caerfai Bay
    Honda Pan-European
    Honda Pan-European
    Honda Pan-European
    A stop at one of my favourite spots, Tan-y-coed
  Later this week I will be living the dream by starting my long-planned motorcycle trip round the US, going into the wild as much as possible, breathing the fresh air, meeting strangers, creating friendships :-D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre US-trip motorcycle warm-up</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/pre-us-trip-motorcycle-warm-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 18:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/pre-us-trip-motorcycle-warm-up/</guid>
      <description>As my riding skills might be a little rusty before my US bike trip in June I decided to get a motorcycle for a few days and travel to Pembrokeshire and back. Started off in Manchester on Saturday morning and took the M56 towards northern Wales.
Great journey but very exhausting at took me much longer than it does in the car, I had to do quite a few stops on the way, on one of them even got to help a fellow French biker near Ruthin who was trying to get to Anglesey .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust storm in Lancashire</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/dust-storm-in-lancashire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 20:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/dust-storm-in-lancashire/</guid>
      <description>Lancashire dirt storm
  This was definitely a first. Not only have I ever seen this meteorological phenomenon, I was never expecting to see it in the UK - the country known for its wet climate.
I was working in a small village in Lancashire but lived on the coast and on my way home I saw these strange dark clouds on the horizon. As I got closer I realised it was clouds of soil and dirt that were being picked up by the strong gusts of wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparations for my bike trip to the USA</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/preparations-for-my-bike-trip-to-the-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 19:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/preparations-for-my-bike-trip-to-the-usa/</guid>
      <description>Harley Davidson Heritage Softail Classic
  This has been a little wish of mine for ages and now that I (seem to) have the money and the time I have decided to go for it. My mental plans started about a year ago when I realised I really needed to pass my motorcycle test n the UK. Not a really silly thought. I met a guy in the lake district, when I was doing my 3-peak challenge, who told me that you could, for an extra fee, just drive in the States on a car driving licence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floreat Salopia</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/floreat-salopia-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 13:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/floreat-salopia-2/</guid>
      <description>Floreat Salopia_ meaning May Shropshire flourish a fitting start of this blog post dedicated to my latest locum job that has taken me to Shrewsbury , the capital of Shropshire . I have never been to Shropshire before and it really was something I needed to amend as it hides some really amazing gems. The most charming, in my opinion, is the before-mentioned medieval capital, about the size of Maribor , that has hundreds of grade listed buildings and lovely narrow streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some more Snowdonia trekking</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/some-more-snowdonia-trekking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 21:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/some-more-snowdonia-trekking/</guid>
      <description>Next to the Watkin path
  Not to repeat myself to many times but I went on a great hiking trip round Snowdonia. Got up way to early and still by the time I came to Nant Gwynant I was still very much in need of sleep. Besides that it was still pouring with rain but there were prospects of sunshine later. So I I did something I haven&amp;rsquo;t so far: crawled in the back of my car, got myself comfortable, opened the windows a little bit and went to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My latest cat bite</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/my-latest-cat-bite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 21:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/my-latest-cat-bite/</guid>
      <description>Not that I think I will be slowly morphing into a human-feline mutant but I was surprised how badly I responded to a recent cat bite I sustained during my locuming in in a small animal practice in Blackpool. Since I graduated from the vet school in 1998 I have had a few bites and lots of scratches from my dearest feline friends but I have never had to seek medical help before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering the Glyders</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/rediscovering-the-glyders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 07:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/rediscovering-the-glyders/</guid>
      <description>Standing on the famous Cantilever on Glyder Fach in Snowdonia
  A couple of years ago I trekked these hills with and came away with a lovely sunburn, sore legs and a great experience. Not unlike this time although I cannot fathom how those UV lights beams were able to penetrate all those clouds yesterday in order to give my skin a damn good uv-light trashing.
The Glyders horseshoe as its also known usually means walking the 4 mountains in one go and this time I did them in this order: Tryfan, Glyer Fach, Glyder Fawr and Y Garn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haverfordwest drivers beware! Well, sort of :-)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/haverfordwest-drivers-beware-well-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 21:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/haverfordwest-drivers-beware-well-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>This is supposed to be a joke but it does depend on how you look at it. It is because on Monday, April 16th, I did my CBT - Compulsory Basic Training for driving a motorcycle and at the end of the training - about 4pm I was set loose on the streets of Haverfordwest.
I would like to apologize to everyone as I kept driving a little to slow or left you waiting because it took me longer than normal to clear a roundabout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ski Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/ski-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 19:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/ski-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>Krvavec
  My recent trip to Slovenia gave me the repeat opportunity to do some skiing again which I was looking forward of doing on the ski resort of Krvavec. I am proud to report no falls or injuries whatsoever.
The place was absolutely packed, probably due to the fact that it was in that weird time between Christmas and New Year and lots of people had the time off work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Carnedds</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/exploring-the-carnedds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 21:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/exploring-the-carnedds/</guid>
      <description>Sunset behind Tryfan
  I returned to to Snowdonia in mid October 2011 to explore the northern third of the Snowdonia range, also known as the Carneddau. They are the most technically demanding part of the Snowdonia range in my opinion but you should not disregard them as there are some really stunning views seen on this range.
When I was returning back to the car park near Llyn Ogwen I was blessed with a spectacular sunset behind the Tryfan mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filming Snow White and the Huntsman at Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/filming-snow-white-and-the-huntsman-at-marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 19:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/filming-snow-white-and-the-huntsman-at-marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>After seeing the filming of Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows and Robin Hood on the Freshwater West beach, Third Star in Barafundle Bay we have again the film crews back in Pembrokeshire for the filming of Snow White and the Huntsman on my favourite beach Marloes Sands .
Filming should be around September 26th - 29th and should mainly involve filming of about 80 horses galloping towards a computer generated castle on Gateholm island .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2011 Three - Day Three - Peak Challenge</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/my-2011-three-peak-challenge-in-three-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 12:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/my-2011-three-peak-challenge-in-three-days/</guid>
      <description>A pit-stop and a warm coffee at Chester M56 services
  OK. My three-peak challenge underway now. One (Snowdon) down, two more to go (Scafell Pike &amp;amp; Ben Nevis). Today&amp;rsquo;s climb on Snowdon was a challenge in itself as it was pissing (yes, not just pouring - PISSING) down with rain. Not one thing I was wearing is currently dry and I am using the car heater to dry as much as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lake of: Now you see it, now you don&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-lake-of-now-you-see-it-now-you-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 20:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-lake-of-now-you-see-it-now-you-dont/</guid>
      <description>Lake Cerknica
  This is about Lake Cerknica - the largest lake in Slovenia, when its there, of course, part of the Notranjska Regional Park . When its there its about 25 km2, but can reach up to 38 km2. It has a complicated system of communications with the underground reservoirs which means the lake can drain and thus completely disappear. It usually fills up after the autumn rains and the spring thaw, and is empty round May and June (sometimes even in winter) so I was lucky to see it when I was there on June 16th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rakov Škocjan</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/rakov-skocjan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 19:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/rakov-skocjan/</guid>
      <description>Rakov Škocjan
  Here is an example of an area I remember visiting as a child and have only vague recollections of it. It is a stunning area in the karst region of Slovenia - the same region where the world famous Postojna caves and Škocjan caves are located, however the Rakov Škocjan park albeit less known to the regular tourist, is still a must see.
  Rakov Škocjan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Miramare estate</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-miramare-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-miramare-estate/</guid>
      <description>This is a stunning castle with surrounding estate close to the northern Italian city of Trieste , close to border with Slovenia .
The Miramare Castle is a stunning Carl Junker designed 19th century castle near the northeastern Italian city of Trieste and was built from 1856 to 1860 for Austrian Archduke Ferdinand Maximilian and his wife, Charlotte of Belgium, later Emperor Maximilian I and Empress Carlota of Mexico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patriarchal Basilica of Aquileia</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/patriarchal-basilica-of-aquileia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 19:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/patriarchal-basilica-of-aquileia/</guid>
      <description>Oglej or Aquileia in Italian is a small village in north-eastern Italy close to the holiday town of Grado (Slovenian: Gradež)
  It is the home of the Patriarchal Basilica of Aquileia which houses the largest and stunning piece of mosaic I have ever seen. Restaurateurs have manufactured an elevated platform and glass walkway inside the basilica allowing you to still walk in the cathedral without walking and ruining the precious mosaic on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Savica falls and Lake Bohinj</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-savica-falls-and-lake-bohinj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 19:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-savica-falls-and-lake-bohinj/</guid>
      <description>This is an old favourite of mine and apparently for many Brits as well as during my short visit there saw countless UK reg cars on the roads.
The Savica waterfall is part of the Sava Bohinjka river which is joined by the Sava Dolinka near Radovljica to form the Sava river . That in turns flows into the Danube at Belgrade which discharges into the Black Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing the M25 car park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/experiencing-the-m25-car-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 18:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/experiencing-the-m25-car-park/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1807&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;620&amp;rdquo;]   M25 parking lot on December 18th Photo: TOMMY HINDLEY[/caption]
There were plenty of warnings about possible weather problems before I set off from Haverfordwest in the SW Wales to Stansted airport on December 18th. There was very little snow in Pembrokeshire and the airport was open. There were absolutely no problems up to the M4 exit for Slough .
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1773&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;225&amp;rdquo;]   Photo taken on my iPhone of the M25 standstill[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 6 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-6-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 17:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-6-of-6/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday. Almost not worth mentioning as I was going to go back home to Haverfordwest . The train from Paddington was strikingly fast and it looked like we were in Bristol in no time. It feels like ages when driving.
However I was supposed to change trains in Newport, Gwent and they have done some modifications to the station and platform assignments meaning I had to cross to the other side using lots of steps to reach the footbridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 5 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-5-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 17:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-5-of-6/</guid>
      <description>Saint Paul&amp;#39;s Cathedral
  Monday. Did some more walking round London and did the touristy view of St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s Cathedral. The Fat Tyre bike tour guide told me that the view from the top of the cathedral was much more impressive than from the London eye. I surely was not disappointed. The tour was not that bad.
  Village Deli in Bermondsey
  The one thing I wanted to do on this day is to go for lunch in Bermondsey .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 4 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-4-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 16:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-4-of-6/</guid>
      <description>BT Tower captured from Oxford Street
  Sunday. Nothing much planned for this day. Did do some shopping but came to Oxford street to early – nobody told me they opened the shops at twelve so I spent some hard earned money at a well-know American coffee franchise called Stardollars or something. The best was left for last as I went to the Natural History Museum and put on a pair of skates after about 17 or 18 years and didn&amp;rsquo;t fall once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 3 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-3-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 15:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-3-of-6/</guid>
      <description>Westminster Hall
  This was a Saturday and the big part of the day was dedicated to the John Rutter &amp;rsquo;s Christmas Celebration at the Royal Albert Hall . This was the second one I have attended and even though the last one I went to was last year it did not feel like a repeat from the previous year. The only difference was to be the Christmas dinner I signed-up</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 2 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-2-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 23:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-2-of-6/</guid>
      <description>You know when you sleep in a strange bed and it takes a night or two before you get used to it. That was exactly what I was doing when at about 6am the first morning the hotel, where I was staying, had its fire alarms go off. When I got into the hall outside my room I saw a lot of sleepy-looking heads popping out from behind the doors trying to find out what the hell was going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 1 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/london-visit-2010-day-1-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 08:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/london-visit-2010-day-1-of-6/</guid>
      <description>London Paddington station during rush hour
  The trip I did last year took quite a bit out of me as I took the car from the deepest and darkest :-) parts of Wales right down the M4 to central London. Now this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be otherwise to bad but for the whole visit being very active and at the end of it was completely exhausted. Not to mention the cold I was nursing at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of the autumn Pembrokeshire snow 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/some-of-the-autumn-pembrokeshire-snow-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 20:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/some-of-the-autumn-pembrokeshire-snow-2010/</guid>
      <description>These photos were taken on a hike to Pentre Ifan this last weekend.
  Pentre Ifan in Pembrokeshire
    Carn Ingli in Pembrokeshire as seen from Pentre Ifan
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My GMail account hacked by 115.52.213.93</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/my-gmail-account-hacked-by-115-52-213-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 21:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/my-gmail-account-hacked-by-115-52-213-93/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately my GMail account martin [dot] mcdowell got somehow hacked today and someone (or something) in China sent a spam message to all my 119 e-mail contacts in my address book at 15.35 this afternoon. The IP address the hack originated from was 115.52.213.93 and is assigned to the Chinese ISP CNC Group CHINA169.
It looks like there was a Google-wide attack as their systems crashed. There are several reports of hacked accounts on Google forums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterfall of the Snow</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/waterfall-of-the-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 06:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/waterfall-of-the-snow/</guid>
      <description>Fullers Falls - Sgwd y Pannwr
  This hike is worth talking about as it takes you round some spectacular views in the Brecon Beacons.
When I did the hike round Cwm Gwesyn the guide books told us about waterfalls but you saw was actually very small - especially compared to the waterfalls seen on this hike between Ystradfellte and Pontneddfechan.
One of the highlights of the walk is the fact that you can walk under one of the waterfalls names Waterfall of the Snow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragična zgodba Tommya Jonesa</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/tragicna-zgodba-tommya-jonesa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/tragicna-zgodba-tommya-jonesa/</guid>
      <description>Gospa Hamer, žena vrtnarja v majhni južno-valežanski vasici, naj bi ponoči sanjala o dečku, ki se je izgubil slab mesec poprej. Ko se je le opogumila in prepričala moža, da ji pomaga, se je 2. septembra leta 1900 skupaj z nekaj sorodniki odpravila na lastno iskalno akcijo. Ko je skupina z gospo Hamer na čelu prispela do grebena nad jezerom Cwm llwch, okoli pol kilometra zahodno od vrha gore Pen-y-fan, je gospa Hammer naenkrat zakričala od groze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the eminence, and then some</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/climbing-the-eminence-and-then-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/climbing-the-eminence-and-then-some/</guid>
      <description>My original plan for this days hike was Y-Garn but that soon changed once I reached the peak and gazed upon the inviting summits of Glyder Fawr and Glyder Fach. As if that was not enough and after all the struggle of descending off Glyder Fach I made a silly move and ascended up Tryfan. Now for those who haven&amp;rsquo;t been up this mountain I must tell you it more resembles a high stack of very big rocks that in many cases precariously lean on each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cwm Gwesyn and the Llyn Brianne reservoir</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</guid>
      <description>This is marked as the toughest walk in the Brecon Becons &amp;amp; South Wales book and it turned out to be living up to its name. The most difficult part was trying to not get lost on Bryn Rhudd at the same time as not loosing interest in the walk as well. The views on there are almost desert-like, nothing but dried grass and boggy moors. Even the sheep are sensible enough not to stray that far from the valleys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dedek Mraz inkognito</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/dedek-mraz-inkognito/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 13:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/dedek-mraz-inkognito/</guid>
      <description>Secret santa je božična navada, ki sem jo opazil v Veliki Britaniji, kjer podariš poljubno izžrebani osebi darilo omejene vrednosti za Dedka mraza. Seveda ta oseba ne ve od koga je dobila darilo, vrednost pa je ponavadi omejena - v našem podjetju smo omejili na 5 funtov.
Za ta Božič sem se odločil, da se pridružim tej navadi in dodal svoj ime na spisek skrivnih božičkov. Slučaj je nanesel, da sem imel zadnji dan službe pred potovanjem v Slovenijo še neke službene obveznosti, moral sem se še dokončno spakirati in se pripraviti na pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stranded sheep in the Blue Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 21:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>The Sunday between Christmas and the New Year I spent hiking around Pembrokeshire and this time I went for walk no. 12 (Around Ynys Barry) taken from the book mentioned in some of my previous posts There is a local attraction called the Blue Lagoon that is just a few minutes away from the Aber Eiddy (also known as Abereiddy) car park where the walk originates from. The lagoon is actually an old man-made slate mining pit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pembrokeshire snow in January 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</guid>
      <description>Had a big snowstorm last night that covered Pembrokeshire with a bit of snow. These photos taken from a hike up to the highest peak in the Preseli hills - Foel Cwmcerwyn . Very windy at the top!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zadenite valežansko gostilno za 20 funtov</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/zadenite-valezansko-gostilno-za-20-funtov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 13:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/zadenite-valezansko-gostilno-za-20-funtov/</guid>
      <description>Danes, 30. septembra 2009, se izteče rok za oddajo vlog za gostilniški netačaj, kjer je glavna in edina nagrada - gostilna sama. Cena za vstop v natečaj je bilo 20 funtov in število sprejetih vlog je omejeno na 30.000.
Kot rečeno bo zmagovalec natečaja postal lastnik gostilne The Plash Inn &amp;amp; Brewery Cottage, ki se nahaja v majceni vasici Llanfallteg v Carmarthenshire-ju v Walesu. Skupna vrednost celotnega objekta je 300.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubijanje v imenu Faktorja X</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ubijanje-v-imenu-faktorja-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 09:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ubijanje-v-imenu-faktorja-x/</guid>
      <description>V Veliki Britaniji že nekaj Božičev zaporedno prihaja na britanski glasbeni lestvici do nadvlade pocukranih komadov iz tovarne pocukranih komadov Simona Cowell-a in njegovega X Factor glasbenega show-a.
Tudi za letošnji Božič je kazalo, da bo zopet zmagal njegov protežiranec in zmagovalec Faktorja X - letos je to uspelo Joe McElderry-u. Račune mu je prekrižala zelo odmevna Facebook kampanija Jona in Tracy Morter, imenovana Rage Against The Machine For Christmas No.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The winter fear of December 18 &amp; 19</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-winter-fear-of-december-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 21:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-winter-fear-of-december-18/</guid>
      <description>After all the worries about traveling from Haverfordwest to Stansted the 5 1/2 hour trip went fine. Blue skies in most of the Wales part, the first snow on the M4 spotted about 6 miles west of the exit for Slough .
The roads are gritted and the only delay was on the M4 exit for the M25 . It looked like a Smart car caught fire. It was being extinguished on the side of the motorway just as I was passing by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 4 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-4-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 19:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-4-of-4/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1453&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;720&amp;rdquo;]   A shark in the big tank in the London Aquarium[/caption]
Not feeling very well in the morning of the last day, this cold has been getting the better of me and running around London does not help it getting any better. Drugging-up with anti-inflammatories not helped either.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1454&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;225&amp;rdquo;]   The London Eye - close to the top[/caption]
First port of call was the London eye I booked the previous day on-line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 3 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-3-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 23:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-3-of-4/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1450&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;640&amp;rdquo;]   The Cabinet War Rooms[/caption]
I started the day a bit more relaxing by taking a slow breakfast at the local Starbucks at London Bridge station opposite Guy&amp;rsquo;s Hospital. A friend told me I had to try the frappucino and their panninis. The guy at the counter asked me twice if I was sure about the frappucino? It is apparently and ice-cold drink and it was the middle of December plus I was bearing a very deep and cold-ridden voice so I wisely opted for a warmer beverage - in this case for a mocha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 2 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-2-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 22:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-2-of-4/</guid>
      <description>After only sleeping a few hours as I only went to bed at 4 am as a consequence from the previous night&amp;rsquo;s walkabout London I had a Fat Tyre bike tour planned for the Saturday morning. The tour takes place on bicycles you get from the tour company and it starts at 11am just outside the Queensway underground station. Its a great way to see the city as you can see different parts of it without walking large distances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 1 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 18:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I soon realised my satnav is going to make me drive down the M4 right into the centre of London - no ifs or butts. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad really, all I had to do is to imagine I was driving downtown Ljubljana - just on a much bigger scale. And it really went very well except at the very end one of the roads was closed and I had to make up a detour on my own - only to get myself even more stuck into the dreaded London rush-hour traffic jams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got bullied by three horses</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/how-i-got-bullied-by-three-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 10:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/how-i-got-bullied-by-three-horses/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1407&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo;]   This is not a photo from the incident[/caption]
Recently I haven not been writing about my treks round Pembrokeshire and how I have been working my way through the &amp;ldquo;Walking in Pembrokeshire &amp;rdquo; guide. I&amp;rsquo;ve done so many now I have been repeating some of them two to three times. This last walk I did for the first time and is worth mentioning as it was one of the more unusual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nepriznavanje kratice dr.vet.med. v Veliki Britaniji</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/nepriznavanje-kratice-dr-vet-med-v-veliki-britaniji/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/nepriznavanje-kratice-dr-vet-med-v-veliki-britaniji/</guid>
      <description>Verjetno bi se mnogemu zdelo vprašanje manjkajoče kratice strokovnega naziva nepomembno ali pa celo na robu postavljaštva. Meni se je to dolgo zdelo in zato nisem ukrenil kaj dosti, ko sem ugotovil, da mi lokalna ustanova, ki kontrolira veterinarje v Veliki Britaniji, Royal college of Veterinary Surgeons ali krajše RCVS, kratice ni dodala v svoj register članov . Trenutno je navedena le kratica MRCVS, kar pomeni &amp;ldquo;Member of the Royal College of Veterinary Surgeons&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netheravon 25. September 2009</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/netheravon-25-september-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 17:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/netheravon-25-september-2009/</guid>
      <description>Back here again, desperately trying to find an FS-1 coach to get my FS-1 license done. Only did one jump today as I developed one very nasty headache and it seems this is one of the rare times I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring any painkillers along.
Oh, what fun ;-)
Beside that the Friday night jumps will commence soon, preparations are under way as I speak (I mean write).
KPICASA_GALLERY(Netheravon)
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydiving after 11 months</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/skydiving-after-11-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 12:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/skydiving-after-11-months/</guid>
      <description>After waiting for 11 months and practically giving up on the notion of jumping out of a plane for the foreseeable future. The given opportunity came last week, Friday off and a sunny forecast. Great weekend.
Managed 7 jumps the Netheravon DZ. Now all I am left to do is to get my FS1 licence as its needed in the UK for jumping in groups.
Didn&amp;rsquo;t take any photos, was a bit worried would get nicked as the DZ is situated on an active military base (technically its an airfield camp ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snemanje Robina Hooda - malce bližje</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-malce-blizje/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 18:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-malce-blizje/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1329&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;446&amp;rdquo;]   Slika z BBC strani, avtorja Scotty[/caption]
Včeraj sem šel spet malo na ogled do lokacije snemanja novega filma o Robinu Hoodu na obali Freshwater West in zadeve so se precej spremenile od prejšnjega tedna, ko sem bil nazadnje tam. Varnostnikov ni bilo veliko in tokrat so me vsaj spustili na plažo, kljub temu, da je na tam potekalo snemanje. Povsod sami statisti, večinoma v horizontali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snemanje Robina Hooda - od daleč</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 19:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</guid>
      <description>V mesecu juniju 2009 so pričeli nedaleč od tod s snemanjem naslednje filmske upodobitve princa tatov - Robina Hooda.
Lokacija, kjer poteka snemanje, se imenuje Freshwater West in gre za eno lepših plaž v Pembrokeshire -ju in Wales-u nasploh. Tu so pejšnji mesec celo snemali naslednji film o Harryu Potterju. Produkcija za Robina Hooda pa je precej večja in vključuje veliko več ljudi in opreme. Pred tedni so imeli v bližnji dvorani avdicijo za statiste in prijaviti se jih je hotelo veliko več, kolikor je bilo mest na voljo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fighting tinnitus and the Ménière syndrome</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/fighting-tinnitus-and-the-meniere-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/fighting-tinnitus-and-the-meniere-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Defined by the British tinnitus association as a ringing, whistling, buzzing and humming in the ears and/or head without any external source it has been a bit of an ailment for me for over a year now. It all started a few years back when I started to get presumably viral related Ménière syndrome attacks. They appeared about once or twice a year and got worse towards the end - the last one &amp;ldquo;flattened&amp;rdquo; me for about 12h with a few days recovery after that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ryanair redeemed by giving refund</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ryanair-redeemed-by-giving-refund/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 17:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ryanair-redeemed-by-giving-refund/</guid>
      <description>Just as I thought I was loosing yet another battle with a faceless corporation filled with robot drones I received some good news the other week.
The dispute I had with Ryanair about a problem with purchasing tickets from their website.Their website crashed and I was left unsure whether I actually purchased the ticket as I could not confirm the reservation through the Ryanair website using my payment details.
After trying contacting Ryanair through various e-mails that apparently don&amp;rsquo;t work I tried writing to Ryanair&amp;rsquo;s corporate head office in Dublin , Ireland .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking the hills of Snowdon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 09:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I moved to Wales 2 years ago I had a quiet wish to climb the highest peak in this country - Snowdon. Last weekend was showing to be a perfect opportunity to fulfil that wish. I was working only till 12 pm and the forecast was for sunshine and high temperatures stretching way into the following week. Getting some good literature , so you know what your are doing, is very advisable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robin Hood filmset all ready at Freshwater West</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/robin-hood-filmset-all-ready-at-freshwater-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 06:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/robin-hood-filmset-all-ready-at-freshwater-west/</guid>
      <description>Second location at the south Freshwater West carpark
  Had the opportunity to have a walk from Angle to the Freshwater West beach and it looks the production team has a lot of logistics to deal with. They seem to have chosen two locations to pitch-up marquees, one is just of the turn from the road to Angle on B4320 and B4319. The second, you could say the main, location is right next to the beach at the southern carpark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hill of Angels</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</guid>
      <description>Looking down towards Cwm mawr
  What a thoroughly enjoyable way to spend a March Sunday. In fact it was so nice I wish the hike would have lasted a bit longer. Instead I took the opportunity to sit and enjoy the sunshine on the wooden bench by the Sychbant car park were this walk starts and ends.
The walk (no. 39: Mynydd Caregog and Carn Ingli) starts off with a nice steep hill and then should continue in a conifer forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhydwilym</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/rhydwilym/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 19:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/rhydwilym/</guid>
      <description>entrance to the mine
  As the book states this is a walk where you can see lots of nice views and hardly meet anyone. And it was true for me. Only people I met were some farmers on a field, however the fact that I did the walk on a Tuesday afternoon might have had something to do with it.
I was especially surprised to see an actual waterfall, not very big but a waterfall nonetheless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Treffgarne Mountain</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</guid>
      <description>This walk seemed the muddiest of them all, in fact I am wandering how exactly to wash my walking shoes and the washing machine is getting to be the favourite. This is the walk no. 32 and can easily be combined with no. 33 (Treffgarne Gorge) as they both start from the same point. That was actually my plan but my walking shoes got filled with lots of lovely mud hindering any furter hikes that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Ryanair website really so bad</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/is-the-ryainair-website-really-so-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 18:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/is-the-ryainair-website-really-so-bad/</guid>
      <description>According to my experience, yes. I tell all Ryanair visitors in advance that this here is my personal opinion and will not allow the publication of rude comments from anyone.
I had the misfortune of booking my flight today only to be confronted with an error just at the point you would least like it - after purchase.
A while ago I found a blog post about a session problem with the Ryanair website here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ko v Britaniji sneži</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ko-v-britaniji-snezi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2009 21:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/ko-v-britaniji-snezi/</guid>
      <description>Puncheston (slikala Lisa Phillips)
  Veliko hecov se je že razvilo na ta račun in ka nekaj sem jih verjetno začel sam. V večini so kar upravičeni in ravno te dni imam to srečo opazovat v praksi, ko v tej državi, v kateri trenutno živim, popadajo v stanje absolutne panike, ko jim pade bela snov iz nebes.
  (slikala Lisa Phillips)
  Kot prvo ne znajo vozit v snegu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carn Llidi</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 11:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</guid>
      <description>Coetan Arthur burial chamber on St Davids Head
  OK, same book used from the last walk , but this time it was walk no. 11: St David&amp;rsquo;s Head and Carn Llidi. You start off at Whitesands near St David which is convenient as there is lots of parking available - you will be charged parking if you come during the tourist season.
The Carn Lidi hill is a prominent feature in southern Pembrokeshire and you can see it from miles away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stonehenge = Made in the Preselis</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/stonehenge-made-in-the-preselis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 18:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/stonehenge-made-in-the-preselis/</guid>
      <description>This morning was going to be a another great day for hiking as the skies were clear and there was no rain forecast for the whole day. I was, again, following the great book Walking in Pembrokeshire - 41 circular walks in the National park. By the way, this was walk no 21: Carn Menyn and the »Bluestones«.
It took me a bit to find the correct site for parking as I kept switching between the book and the Ordnance survey map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiing on Vogel</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skiing-on-vogel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 20:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skiing-on-vogel/</guid>
      <description>Started off while it was still dark. Plan A was going to ski on Krvavec. No plan B at that time. Just as we left Cerklje there was a suspicious hold-up in the traffic which turned out to be due to the great number of cars - all heading for the same ski resort. My friend and I parked just soon after Cerklje , where the buses usually park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 07:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>I have tried to visit this place before but the last time got a bit disappointed as there was the standard parking fee . Today was a very good time to see the place, sunny and not a lot of people on it. Oh yes, and the parking was free. By the way, I am all for conservation and good old cash goes a long way in conservation but ripping local of so that they can use the local nature is just wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</guid>
      <description>I have now managed to send off the container to the manufacturer Aerodyne in Florida . I have just driven back from Swansea where I send off the container through a DHL ServicePoint location in the Parc Tawe Staples shop. Great service, if you ask me, as you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay a high price to have your packed shipped and you also choose what boy its going to be sent in - the price of shipment depends on the size of the box, but with a upper weight limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 19:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</guid>
      <description>My recent visit to the motherland gave me the opportunity for yet another skydiving session, I joined my instructor and mentor Aleš Debeljak from the Paranoia skydiving school.
All went well and on the third jump of the second day just as I exited the Cessna 206 I apparently managed to hook my rig on the side of the door which resulted in a nasty tear in my container on the reserve parachute flap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swalec and a gas meter reading error</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/swalec-and-a-gas-meter-reading-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 15:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/swalec-and-a-gas-meter-reading-error/</guid>
      <description>This will be my public consumer awareness post. Just for those who don&amp;rsquo;t know me, I have not lived in the UK for many years so I had no real idea how much utilities cost. Sure you can compare prices between different companies but its difficult to know, how much you spend.
However I always thought I was paying a bit to much for gas but was delaying the time to actually call up the gas copmany and ask for some help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sands of speed</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 16:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</guid>
      <description>This is the name of a 7 mile (11 km) stretch of sandy beach located on the south Wales coastline between Tenby and Swansea . The most impressive feature of this beach is its flatness and straightness at such a long length. You can see the satellite view below.
In the early 20th century the sands were often used as a racing course and later, in the 1920s, it was used for land speed records .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The red dragon will lead the way</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-red-dragon-will-lead-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 19:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-red-dragon-will-lead-the-way/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_736&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;576&amp;rdquo;]   The Pierhead building in Cardiff Bay[/caption]
Always wanted to see the capital of Wales but always ended up just drive pass it on the M4. The closest I ever got to the actual city centre was to visit the local Ikea store while I was still in the process of furnishing my small flat in Haverfordwest.
Here are some more detailed instructions for those who might want to see it also but don&amp;rsquo;t know how to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenby</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_656&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;800&amp;rdquo;]   Tenby harbour with the Quay on left, lifeboat station above it, Castle Hill in the centre top[/caption]
I have put it off for a long time but a sightee-er to Tenby was well due. The town of Tenby lies on the south Pembrokeshire coast and if leaving from Haverfordwest can take the road across the Cledau bridge or you can, by saving the 75p bridge toll and, depriving the Pembrokeshire County Council :-), go through Canaston Bridge .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmap-ing me</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/schmaping-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 19:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/schmaping-me/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_639&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;]   The photo of Bristol Cathedral chosen for the fifth edition of the Schmap Bristol Guide[/caption]
I received a mail today from an on-line publisher of digital travel guides called Schmap that my photo of Bristol Cathedral was chosen to be included in the fifth edition of the Schmap Bristol Guide .
I received an e-mail a while ago saying that the photo was short-listed for it and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think my photos were good enough for somebody to publish them in a guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prinesite svoje bolne živali</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/prinesite-svoje-bolne-zivali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2008 17:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/prinesite-svoje-bolne-zivali/</guid>
      <description>Živim v državi, kjer imajo že večletno zgodovino zavesti za boljšo skrb živali. To sicer morda vsakogar ne bi prepričalo po branju člankov o večletni tradiciji brutalnih lovov na lisice , so pa nasprotno precej bolj strpni in dobrodelni do hišnih ljubljencev in konjev in bi marsikaj storili za njihovo blagostanje.
Ravno ta teden smo se namreč na kliniki, kjer delam, pridružili projektu DogsTrust -a, ki to poletje nudi kastracijo/sterilizacijo ter mikročipiranje za zgolj 10 funtov (okoli €12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Message from John Cleese to the Citizens of the US</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/to-the-citizens-of-the-united-states-of-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/to-the-citizens-of-the-united-states-of-america/</guid>
      <description>I saw this somewhere on the internet and found it hilarious. I apologise to any US citizen if he/she is offended but this is really good!
 To The citizens of the United States of America :
In light of your failure to nominate competent candidates for President of the USA and thus to govern yourselves, we hereby give notice of the revocation of your independence, effective immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Queen to visit Slovenia</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 18:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-queen-to-visit-slovenia/</guid>
      <description>I was very surprised to hear that the British Queen Elisabeth II . is to visit Slovenia soon.
 Buckingham Palace press releases
ANNOUNCEMENT OF STATE VISITS TO SLOVENIA AND SLOVAKIA
26 June 2008
THE FOLLOWING STATEMENT IS ISSUED BY THE PRESS SECRETARY TO THE QUEEN
 T&amp;gt; he Queen and The Duke of Edinburgh will pay State Visits to: Slovenia, at the invitation of President Dr Danilo Tuerk ; and Slovakia , at the invitation of President Ivan Gasparovic , during this Autumn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PST od Johnstona do Neylanda</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/pst-od-johnstona-do-neylanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 12:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/pst-od-johnstona-do-neylanda/</guid>
      <description>Prejšnji torek sem delal samo pol dneva in sem izkoristil to priložnost da sem končno opravil pešpot od Johnstona, kraja kjer živim, do Neylanda . Oba kraja sta namreč povezana s precej lepo kolesarsko stezo, ki pa je odprta tudi za pešce. Pot je približno dolga 6,5 km in se vije po prelepi valežanski pokrajini. Sicer valežanska pot ne bi bila prava, če ne bi bila levo in desno obdana s kako ograjo ali nasipom in tudi ta ni izjema, amapk pustmo to - dan je bil lep in dejmo pot pot noge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6 in Deland - a great day for jumping</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-6-in-deland-a-great-day-for-jumping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2008 02:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-6-in-deland-a-great-day-for-jumping/</guid>
      <description>The morning was a bit foggy but that soon cleared and the weather hold on the jumps was lifted by about 11am. Then we went full throttle as we knwe we might have another weather related bad jump day tomorrow. I managed to make a record 8 jumps, the last one being the sunset jump. Usually they are at a higher altitude but this one was the same as the others, nevertheless it was completely full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 in Deland - back in the air again</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-5-in-deland-back-in-the-air-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-5-in-deland-back-in-the-air-again/</guid>
      <description>The morning had low clouds but we hoped that they would soon lift and that we would see blue skies again - unfortunately this took much longer than first predicted as we started jumping at about 1PM.
As it was a Sunday most of the skydivers wanted to make the most of the day and the DZ became very busy as there were 3 planes flying at any given time (Twin Otter, PAC 820, Skyvan or Porter), today we saw the first appearance of the Skyvan .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive Sebastian</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skydive-sebastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skydive-sebastian/</guid>
      <description>As we woke this morning we could only take a depressing glance out of the window and despair over the rubbish weather we had. It was bucketing down. We had to decide either to stay in the house, go on a (inside) sightseeing tour, or drive to a DZ that does not have bad weather. We chose on the latter and decided to go to Skydive Sebastian - a DZ located in the Florida town called Sebastian (duh) just over 2 hours drive from Deland, passing Titusville and Cape Canaveral on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 in Deland</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-deland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2008 02:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-deland/</guid>
      <description>The weather, again, was a bit of a disappointment. In the morning we were not sure if we should bother even going to the DZ. Our landlord Dennis said that the clouds should break up. When we came there the DZ was closed for jumps and it looked like nobody was going to jump today.
However later in the afternoon the clouds cleared and I managed to do 2 jumps, the winds were quite strong and sometimes unpredictable, but I was quite pleased with my landings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 in Deland (really spent in Daytona Beach)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-deland-really-spent-in-daytona-beach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 01:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-deland-really-spent-in-daytona-beach/</guid>
      <description>As the weather wasn&amp;rsquo;t very promising most of us managed to do only two jumps, the last one in many cases being in the rain and believe me, it is not nice or romantic to free fly through rain. It feels like you are being pricked with pins all over your face. I did a couple of three-way jump with Miha and Barbara and I think it went well considering our experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 at Deland</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-2-at-deland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 02:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-2-at-deland/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have got my reserve deployment out of the way I can get to some good and proper skydiving. Managed to get the record number of jumps for a day - 5 and I could have done at least one more but I had to arrange another rental car for our group.
The picture on the left is showing our makeshift hangar - the flag has now been moved to a proper flag post close to the boarding zone - pics to follow :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first parachute reserve</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/my-first-parachute-reserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 04:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/my-first-parachute-reserve/</guid>
      <description>Not only was it my first jump at Deland or in the U.S. in general, but it also ended up being the jump that I had to deploy my reserve. The jump started well as a 5-way group with the local instructor Carl. We broke off the formation at 1.500 m and opened at approx. 1.200 - 1.000 m. The parachute opened a bit slower than usual but I very quickly realized something was very wrong, the canopy was making me go in circles, but not spirals, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t loosing height quickly but it all came down to my first cell from the left (the parachute is a 7-cell Atair Dragon 170).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4 in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-4-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>Feeling better after the midnights tunnel session, still having problems with some of the techniques but my instructor Aljaž says there are visible improvements. I hope so as I sometimes feel like a sack of potatoes in a tornado when I&amp;rsquo;m in the tunnel.
Today marks the end of the tunnel sessions for most of us as our group will be moving out of the hotel and heading up to Deland, FL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>This is getting to be really tough. Last nights session started at midnight and I somewhat remember going to bed at 2am. This morning there are another three sessions, the first one on which starts at 9am. I am well and truly sore all over and hadn&amp;rsquo;t had this much physical exercise in a good few years.
Most of us, who are doing RW work in the tunnel don&amp;rsquo;t have much time to do anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first Saturday in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-first-saturday-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-first-saturday-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>No real time to do anything else here as most of the time is spent either briefing for the tunnel, debriefing for the tunnel or actually IN the tunnel. I have hardly any time to eat - in fact I have only eaten once - yesterday&amp;rsquo;s breakfast - and that is it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-day-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 05:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-day-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>The wind tunnel training started a day before I expected so I had to get up at about 6am. I did 5x2 minutes in the morning, then another 5x2 minutes in the afternoon and I have just completed another 2x2 minutes session. I have now finished debriefing and it is ten minutes to one in the morning! By my home watch it is just before 6am!
Don&amp;rsquo;t even think that flying in a wind tunnel is easy and not exhausting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First leg to Florida: Hickstead</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-leg-to-florida-hickstead/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/first-leg-to-florida-hickstead/</guid>
      <description>Here I am, in lovely Hickstead, somewhere between Crawley (Gatwick airport) and Brighton in the local Travelodge . Took me about four and a half hours to get here from Haverfordwest and I can sincerely say, I am nackered. The drive was very smooth although I knew I was going to be hitting the London&amp;rsquo;s circular road (the M25) at rush hour. My satnav took me from the M4 via a shortcut to the M3 and then on the M25.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moje prve ure Valežanščine</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/moje-prve-ure-valezanscine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2008 10:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/moje-prve-ure-valezanscine/</guid>
      <description>Ker se uradno tečaji pričnejo šele jeseni in ker se mi do takrat ravno ne čaka, sem se odločil iti na krajši enodnevni tečaj Valežanščine v lokalnem družbenem učnem centru tu, v Haverfordwestu. Na začetku je bilo malo zmede, ko so nas začeli razporejati v skupine - v Valežanščini, kar pa je malce problem glede na to, da nimam pojma o tem jeziku. Čisto lahko, da so govorili v močnem valežanskem narečju angleščine, vendar po pravici povem, da, tudi drugi ne-valežani, niso zlahka opazili razliko.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song for our Antonov - Anova pesem (article on Playboy.si)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/song-for-our-antonov-anova-pesem-article-on-playboysi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/song-for-our-antonov-anova-pesem-article-on-playboysi/</guid>
      <description>The Slovene edition of Playboy issued a great article in rememberence of our dear pilot Som and our Fata (to know more about this please read the following articles: article 1: »Fata« and »Som« have left us ; article 2: A great tragedy ). The Playboy article was written by Sabina Mali , Miss Hawaiian Tropic 2007 and is, unfortunately for you English speakers, only written in Slovene. Perhaps an English translation will be available in the future - at least the video is worth watching- see our late Som and Fata in action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great tragedy</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/a-great-tragedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/a-great-tragedy/</guid>
      <description>As usual some of the media outlets are taking a completely wrong ignorant spin on this genuine and sad tragedy.
Slovenia lost a great pilot Viktor Bečan (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo;). My sincere condolences go to his family. My hopes for a quick recovery go to the surviving co-pilot Savo Medved
Photo on left featuring the &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo; made by Lubi in Novo mesto (Prečna) in June 2007.
Slovenia lost a legend among skydiving planes the &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo; - Antonov 2 from the Paranoia Skydiving school (part of the ŠOLT organization) that fulfilled the dreams of many skydivers in becoming the vessel for them to do their first skydive jumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>»Fata« and »Som« have left us</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/fata-and-som-have-left-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/fata-and-som-have-left-us/</guid>
      <description>I must sadly inform you that the Antonov-2 airplane (we lovingly called &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo;) from which I learned how to skydive and did many jumps, the most recent ones in September 2007, crashed in the mountains near Trbovlje at about 1pm local time.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_350&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;]   Photo taken by Daniel Zavratnik in Bovec in August 2007. Viktor Bečan a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo; is the chap on the left in a green t-shirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moje prvo srečanje z lokalnim nesocialnim vedenjem</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/moje-prvo-srecanje-z-lokalnim-nesocialnim-vedenjem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2007 13:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/moje-prvo-srecanje-z-lokalnim-nesocialnim-vedenjem/</guid>
      <description>Sem upal, da se mi ne bo potrebno srečati s to precej pogosto obliko vedenja v tem delu Velike Britanije, zal pa se je izkazalo, da tudi ta samotni Johnston, v katerem živim, ni imun na tovrstno obliko izživljanja mladih.
Da najprej malo objasnim našo okolico. Živim v dvostanovanjski hiši, neposredno poleg mene se zgradba nadaljuje in v vsaki od teh vrstnih hiš sta dve stanovanji. Drugi sklop zgradb so enostanovanjske hiše, vendar približno enako velike, kot na naši strani.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive London for a day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I did what I wanted to do for a long while - to actually skydive in the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting it off for a long time, lately mostly due to the weather we have been having. Last weekend the weather was OK, no flu lingering in the background and no lameness in any of the legs :-) The Skydive London dropzone is situated about 3 hours drive away from Haverfordwest , adjacent to the town of Swindon .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To have a face on Facebook</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/to-have-a-face-on-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/to-have-a-face-on-facebook/</guid>
      <description>I have joined the hoard of internet users around the world and started using Facebook . I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it much but so far I am very impressed in the overall system. Really well thought out and programed. No wonder Google and Microsoft have appetites in the company. It is assumed to be worth around 10 billion USD . The company was founded by a student drop-off in 2004 and currently has 42 million active users and more than 14 million photos are uploaded daily to the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return to skydiving</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/return-to-skydiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/return-to-skydiving/</guid>
      <description>After a one year sebaticle I finally got the chance to do some skydiving again. The best thing about it, besides, of course, skydiving, was that I could do it at my old home drop zone Prečna in Novo mesto in the southern part of Slovenia. The other good part was that I could jump from the old Antonov 2 (the one we use bares the nickname &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo; and here is a picture of it in action).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnston 2 Ljubljana = 2080 km</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/johnston-2-ljubljana-2080-km/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2007 08:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/johnston-2-ljubljana-2080-km/</guid>
      <description>Started off from a sunny Johnston on Sunday at about 11.25 am and arrived in Ljubljana early this morning at about 1 am. The trip took me all through Pembrokeshire and the south of Wales, crossing the second Severn bridge to England while on the M4 , getting to London and then down to Folkestone in Kent to pick up the Channel tunnel train to Calais where I slept over .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Še en teden do odhoda</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/se-en-teden-do-odhoda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2007 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/se-en-teden-do-odhoda/</guid>
      <description>No, še ta teden gre mimo, potem pa grem na pot. Če bo šlo vse po načrtih, se odpravim v nedeljo zjutraj in se vmes ustavim še pri očetu, nato pa do Folkestone-a na vlak, ki pelje pod Rokavskim prelivom, potem pa v tem vrstnem redu: Francija, Belgija, Nizozemska, Nemčija, Avstrija in potem domača Slovenija. Ne morem ravno reči rodna, bi pa z veseljem.
Tipična fora pri Murphiju: ravno v petek sem imel servis za novega Passata, v začetku tedna pa začutim, da mi v Golfu nagajajo zavore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Končno, selitev</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/koncno-selitev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/koncno-selitev/</guid>
      <description>Razmere v hiši, kjer živim trenutno, so bile malo preveč »zanimive« in še ponavljajoči se kiksi lastnika (landlorda) so mi šli že pošteno na živce. V lokalnem časopisu sem že nekaj tednov iskal morebitno novo lokacijo in si jih tudi nekaj ogledal. Na koncu pa mi je bilo še najbolj všeč stanovanje v čisto novi hiši nedaleč od kraja, kjer trenutno živim.
Ponujeno mi je bilo ali stanovanje v pritličju ali stanovanje v 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No smoking, please</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</guid>
      <description>I see that Slovenia is quite behind the smoking ban that is in the process of being inforced across the EU . I arrived in Wales on the 7th of April and that was the weekend, when the ban started here . There was no big deal, however we will see what will happen in a few months time when the temperature drops. The ban was enforced just before the summer and it was followed by a very warm period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bodyflight Bedford indoor skydiving [or how to fly around a room and not having a hangover the next day]</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/bodyflight-bedford-indoor-skydiving-or-how-to-fly-around-a-room-and-not-having-a-hangover-the-next-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/bodyflight-bedford-indoor-skydiving-or-how-to-fly-around-a-room-and-not-having-a-hangover-the-next-day/</guid>
      <description>It was a great day probably more suitable for outdoor skydiving than indoor skydiving. I set of from home early Saturday morning and arrived at Bedford five and a half hours later after stupidly ignoring my satnav and adding another hour to my already long journey. The Bodyflight facility is situated in a generally abandoned ex-military complex outside of Bedford near the A6. I heard it was used to do tests for the Concorde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My second start as a vet</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/my-second-start-as-a-vet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2007 15:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/my-second-start-as-a-vet/</guid>
      <description>Closer I got to starting to work at the vet clinic , the more I dreaded the moment and the more I felt not being up for the job seeing that I haven&amp;rsquo;t practised vet medicine for so long. The first day of worked showed me, how much I great team of co-workers can help, when you are not sure of your own abilities to get the job done.
I was afraid about performing operations as I had little experience from before, but I actually did so much on the first day and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the feeling I was doing something I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really supposed so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The trip to Wales (the UK)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 15:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>I reserved a hotel in Ashford and it took me less than half an hour to get there from Folkstone – the UK side of the Channel tunnel. It was 1 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning CET :-( I was a bit worried leaving all my stuff in the car on an unsecured parking lot and at about 4.30 in the morning I got a scare as I woke up and heard a car alarm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The trip to Wales (from the The Netherlands to the Channel tunnel)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-from-the-the-netherlands-to-the-channel-tunnel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-from-the-the-netherlands-to-the-channel-tunnel/</guid>
      <description>The trip got a bit boring after that, I knew the German part was ending soon as I passed Aachen. The Dutch part was completely uneventful, but I did get some pictures on a lay-by of absolutely nothing interesting.
After that came Belgium and Brussels with it. I heard of people missing the circular road round Brussels and I nearly missed it using the sat-nav. The drivers around Brussels are just about ready for being committed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The trip to Wales (Germany)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-germany/</guid>
      <description>I watched a documentary on one of the satellite channels a while ago about the might of the Germany autobahns and well they are constructed. I even remember how good they were the last time I used them on the trip to Scotland in 1999. This time, however, it was obvious, that they can be quite bad. After Munich the motorway took me towards Stuttgart and road was really bad: no breakdown lane, the speed limit was only 120 km/h or less and close to Stuttgart there was one work site after the other so most of that part was driven on a contraflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The trip to Wales (Ljubljana to Salzburg)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-ljubljana-to-salzburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-trip-to-wales-ljubljana-to-salzburg/</guid>
      <description>After having a chance to get my bearings I have finally got finger to keyboard to write about the trip. Unfortunately I still do not have an internet connection and despite having a wireless-enables laptop I still cannot get to use someone&amp;rsquo;s wireless router to get online. Sorry folks but desperate times call for desperate measures. I heard a while ago that many used unsecured WiFi networks but where the hell are they when you really need them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reserve parachute and AAD</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/reserve-parachute-and-aad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/reserve-parachute-and-aad/</guid>
      <description>Now it seem to be all happening. I received the PD reserve 160 and the Cypres 2 Expert 1-pin AAD last week. I would expect the Cypres to come in a nice packet, which it did, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a clue how the parachute would be packed. Well, it literally came &amp;ldquo;as is&amp;rdquo;. I put it in a bag myself so it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get stained or damaged - not that a plastic bag is any real protection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The skydiving grandma</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-skydiving-grandma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2007 09:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-skydiving-grandma/</guid>
      <description>This is not a news story about a lady who was given a gift voucher to do a tandem jump. No, no, this actualy my mother, who is, by the way, also a three-time grandmother, who bought herself a skydiving course here, in Slovenia, and actually finished it the next year when she passed the skydiving exam and became a proper licensed skydiver. This is no small matter even for the school itself, the school is called Paranoia and is part of the Šolt organization and is ran by Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this 21st century plumbing?</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/is-this-21st-century-plumbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2007 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/is-this-21st-century-plumbing/</guid>
      <description>A colleague of mine a few years ago took a business trip to the United Kingdom and upon his return he described what was his experience like. And he didn&amp;rsquo;t even complain much about the food (you should see the food we get in Slovenia) but what he just could not understand was the British odd sense of common household plumbing.
This rang a bell with me as I have been puzzled on many occasions by the strange water systems the British have as an excuse for decent plumbing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ghost B&amp;B</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-ghost-bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 12:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/the-ghost-bb/</guid>
      <description>I had some business to attend to in the UK at the end of last week and I made a reservation with a bed and breakfast near the village of Cheddleton in northern England. As the booking was done just under two weeks prior to my arrival, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think it necessary to re-check. But then I got to &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; place I thought was the B&amp;amp;B after driving all day long and being completely knackered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The curse of the Christmas cards</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-curse-of-the-christmas-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 12:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-curse-of-the-christmas-cards/</guid>
      <description>The story repeats itself every year. If you are savvy enough to start thinking which cards you intend to buy and for whom, the whole nonsense can begin as early as November. You can&amp;rsquo;t really stop thinking about it or even forget the whole thing as the absence of cards from you will eventually be noticed, especially if you still appear to be among the living. You could start outright lying that you converted to Islam and that you do not recognize the whole Christmas period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The London trip 2006 (days 4 and 5)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-days-4-and-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-days-4-and-5/</guid>
      <description>These two days were mainly spent doing other stuff, but one of the things, that ended to be taking up quite a bit of my time was the search for the sodden curry powder. You know when you go abroad and you sometimes get a list of things to buy. I had Sharwoods mild curry powder on this one (among other things) and unlike a few years ago, when it was quite easy to find it in Tesco, this time it proved to be mission impossible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The London trip 2006 (day 3)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Finally, I had much less to do today, unless you include driving - most of it on the M11, M25 and M3, M27 motorway (in that order). And the weather improved so I got to see that rarely seen English sunshine. I never stop being surprised on the size of the road and the chaotic sense of the M25. Cars keep on coming up to you from all directions and it is no place to be thinking of how last years boogie in Maribor went as you may find you are suddenly united by at least one car who&amp;rsquo;s driver was probably thinking about tonight&amp;rsquo;s supper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The London trip 2006 (day 2)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2006 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-day-2/</guid>
      <description>OK, this time it was for real. No more messing about with strange-side-of-the-steering-wheel car and funny gear sticks that didn&amp;rsquo;t want to move. I had to get to London, find parking, get to the Redbridge tube station, change at Mile End, end up in Westiminster station, walk to the Royal College of Veterinary Surgeons (RCVS) and get myself registered. Luckily the London underground is just to big too big to implement any real security checks so I was spared the man handling I had to endure the previous day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The London trip 2006 (day 1)</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2006 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/the-london-trip-2006-day-1/</guid>
      <description>If you asked me a few months ago that I will have to go to the UK I would not be so cheerful as the security checks at the airports would probably be as pleasant as sticking your hand in a meat grinder. Luckily the EU recently imposed new regulations that make air travel a bit easier, just as long as you stick all your aftershaves and deodorants in the check-in luggage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OK, go</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/ok-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2006 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2006/ok-go/</guid>
      <description>Well, so far I never had any need to publish a blog whatsoever. I created the blogspot just to see what it looks alike and how Google has organized things. I have done much blogging but sorry to say the Blogspot.com leaves a lot to be desired. Hopefully they will put as much work into this as they did in Google Docs, which by the way is a great tool. It is very simple so don&amp;rsquo;t compare it to OpenOffice or Microsoft Office Excel, but it does some very good basic things and it is accessible everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
