<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wales on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/wales/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wales on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 20:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/wales/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cwm Gwesyn and the Llyn Brianne reservoir</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</guid>
      <description>This is marked as the toughest walk in the Brecon Becons &amp;amp; South Wales book and it turned out to be living up to its name. The most difficult part was trying to not get lost on Bryn Rhudd at the same time as not loosing interest in the walk as well. The views on there are almost desert-like, nothing but dried grass and boggy moors. Even the sheep are sensible enough not to stray that far from the valleys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pembrokeshire snow in January 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</guid>
      <description>Had a big snowstorm last night that covered Pembrokeshire with a bit of snow. These photos taken from a hike up to the highest peak in the Preseli hills - Foel Cwmcerwyn . Very windy at the top!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zadenite valežansko gostilno za 20 funtov</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/zadenite-valezansko-gostilno-za-20-funtov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 13:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/zadenite-valezansko-gostilno-za-20-funtov/</guid>
      <description>Danes, 30. septembra 2009, se izteče rok za oddajo vlog za gostilniški netačaj, kjer je glavna in edina nagrada - gostilna sama. Cena za vstop v natečaj je bilo 20 funtov in število sprejetih vlog je omejeno na 30.000.
Kot rečeno bo zmagovalec natečaja postal lastnik gostilne The Plash Inn &amp;amp; Brewery Cottage, ki se nahaja v majceni vasici Llanfallteg v Carmarthenshire-ju v Walesu. Skupna vrednost celotnega objekta je 300.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snemanje Robina Hooda - od daleč</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 19:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</guid>
      <description>V mesecu juniju 2009 so pričeli nedaleč od tod s snemanjem naslednje filmske upodobitve princa tatov - Robina Hooda.
Lokacija, kjer poteka snemanje, se imenuje Freshwater West in gre za eno lepših plaž v Pembrokeshire -ju in Wales-u nasploh. Tu so pejšnji mesec celo snemali naslednji film o Harryu Potterju. Produkcija za Robina Hooda pa je precej večja in vključuje veliko več ljudi in opreme. Pred tedni so imeli v bližnji dvorani avdicijo za statiste in prijaviti se jih je hotelo veliko več, kolikor je bilo mest na voljo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking the hills of Snowdon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 09:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I moved to Wales 2 years ago I had a quiet wish to climb the highest peak in this country - Snowdon. Last weekend was showing to be a perfect opportunity to fulfil that wish. I was working only till 12 pm and the forecast was for sunshine and high temperatures stretching way into the following week. Getting some good literature , so you know what your are doing, is very advisable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hill of Angels</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</guid>
      <description>Looking down towards Cwm mawr
  What a thoroughly enjoyable way to spend a March Sunday. In fact it was so nice I wish the hike would have lasted a bit longer. Instead I took the opportunity to sit and enjoy the sunshine on the wooden bench by the Sychbant car park were this walk starts and ends.
The walk (no. 39: Mynydd Caregog and Carn Ingli) starts off with a nice steep hill and then should continue in a conifer forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Treffgarne Mountain</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</guid>
      <description>This walk seemed the muddiest of them all, in fact I am wandering how exactly to wash my walking shoes and the washing machine is getting to be the favourite. This is the walk no. 32 and can easily be combined with no. 33 (Treffgarne Gorge) as they both start from the same point. That was actually my plan but my walking shoes got filled with lots of lovely mud hindering any furter hikes that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carn Llidi</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 11:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</guid>
      <description>Coetan Arthur burial chamber on St Davids Head
  OK, same book used from the last walk , but this time it was walk no. 11: St David&amp;rsquo;s Head and Carn Llidi. You start off at Whitesands near St David which is convenient as there is lots of parking available - you will be charged parking if you come during the tourist season.
The Carn Lidi hill is a prominent feature in southern Pembrokeshire and you can see it from miles away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 07:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>I have tried to visit this place before but the last time got a bit disappointed as there was the standard parking fee . Today was a very good time to see the place, sunny and not a lot of people on it. Oh yes, and the parking was free. By the way, I am all for conservation and good old cash goes a long way in conservation but ripping local of so that they can use the local nature is just wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sands of speed</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 16:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</guid>
      <description>This is the name of a 7 mile (11 km) stretch of sandy beach located on the south Wales coastline between Tenby and Swansea . The most impressive feature of this beach is its flatness and straightness at such a long length. You can see the satellite view below.
In the early 20th century the sands were often used as a racing course and later, in the 1920s, it was used for land speed records .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The red dragon will lead the way</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-red-dragon-will-lead-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 19:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-red-dragon-will-lead-the-way/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_736&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;576&amp;rdquo;]   The Pierhead building in Cardiff Bay[/caption]
Always wanted to see the capital of Wales but always ended up just drive pass it on the M4. The closest I ever got to the actual city centre was to visit the local Ikea store while I was still in the process of furnishing my small flat in Haverfordwest.
Here are some more detailed instructions for those who might want to see it also but don&amp;rsquo;t know how to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenby</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_656&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;800&amp;rdquo;]   Tenby harbour with the Quay on left, lifeboat station above it, Castle Hill in the centre top[/caption]
I have put it off for a long time but a sightee-er to Tenby was well due. The town of Tenby lies on the south Pembrokeshire coast and if leaving from Haverfordwest can take the road across the Cledau bridge or you can, by saving the 75p bridge toll and, depriving the Pembrokeshire County Council :-), go through Canaston Bridge .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No smoking, please</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</guid>
      <description>I see that Slovenia is quite behind the smoking ban that is in the process of being inforced across the EU . I arrived in Wales on the 7th of April and that was the weekend, when the ban started here . There was no big deal, however we will see what will happen in a few months time when the temperature drops. The ban was enforced just before the summer and it was followed by a very warm period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
