<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 13:29:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fighting tinnitus and the Ménière syndrome</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/fighting-tinnitus-and-the-meniere-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/fighting-tinnitus-and-the-meniere-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Defined by the British tinnitus association as a ringing, whistling, buzzing and humming in the ears and/or head without any external source it has been a bit of an ailment for me for over a year now. It all started a few years back when I started to get presumably viral related Ménière syndrome attacks. They appeared about once or twice a year and got worse towards the end - the last one &amp;ldquo;flattened&amp;rdquo; me for about 12h with a few days recovery after that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To have a face on Facebook</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/to-have-a-face-on-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/to-have-a-face-on-facebook/</guid>
      <description>I have joined the hoard of internet users around the world and started using Facebook . I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it much but so far I am very impressed in the overall system. Really well thought out and programed. No wonder Google and Microsoft have appetites in the company. It is assumed to be worth around 10 billion USD . The company was founded by a student drop-off in 2004 and currently has 42 million active users and more than 14 million photos are uploaded daily to the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No smoking, please</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 18:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/no-smoking-please/</guid>
      <description>I see that Slovenia is quite behind the smoking ban that is in the process of being inforced across the EU . I arrived in Wales on the 7th of April and that was the weekend, when the ban started here . There was no big deal, however we will see what will happen in a few months time when the temperature drops. The ban was enforced just before the summer and it was followed by a very warm period.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
