<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trips and outings on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/trips-and-outings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trips and outings on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 21:08:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/trips-and-outings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brecon beacons: Cribyn - Pen-y-fan - Corn Du</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/brecon-beacons-cribyn-pen-y-fan-corn-du/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 21:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/brecon-beacons-cribyn-pen-y-fan-corn-du/</guid>
      <description>Modified the usual hike that goes straight up from the Cwm Gwdi carpark. Elevation gain 914 m.
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Viševnik, 2,050m</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-visevnik-2050m/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 19:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-visevnik-2050m/</guid>
      <description>An old favourite. Have been up it only twice before as far as I can remember. The last time it was a scorching hot summers day and this is also when I learned about dogs and how peculiar they can be be.
I took our family dog with me and to make sure we were both hydrated I took a bottle of water for her and a bottle of flavoured water for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Krim 1,107m</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-krim-1107m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-krim-1107m/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps not as prominent of a mountain as the other ones you could climb in the alps but a good training ground. Funny enough quite comparable to the Snowdon hike. Krim is 1,107 metres tall and you start the hike from Iški Vintgar at 420m so a height climb of about 750m. The climb from Pen-y-pass (559 m) to Snowdon (1,085 m) is about 526 metres or 817 metres if you start from Llyn Gwynant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mt. Debela Peč, 1,014m</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-debela-pec-1014m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 19:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/mt-debela-pec-1014m/</guid>
      <description>A great hike up a stunning mountain. The drive to the small carpark in the middle of nowhere is an experience in itself. Then you set off up a disused track and end up in a large open area called Klek plateau.
This is where the tricky part comes in, the most difficult part of the trip is the navigation. Trying to find the exit point to the path continuing towards the peaks of Debela Pec and Lipanca.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puncture prevented further training</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/puncture-prevented-further-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 19:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/puncture-prevented-further-training/</guid>
      <description>I had a bit of an eventful day today. Set of to hike up Pen y fan , had to find a way out of town as there were was a road closure and ended up going a way I don&amp;rsquo;t usually use. Somewhere on that trip I must have ridden over something sharp. By the time I got to Leominster about 20 minutes away I felt the bike being unstable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for new boots</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/time-for-new-boots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 19:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/time-for-new-boots/</guid>
      <description>I had to bite the bullet and try finding some good boots that will last me for the training I have to do plus be suitable for the Kilimanjaro trip, so hot savannah and ice cold Uhuru peak.
   I knew I was going to need some help and I was dreading having to go to one of the big corps and one of their outlets. I needed some proper help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The full Malverns, up and down</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/the-full-malverns-up-and-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 19:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/the-full-malverns-up-and-down/</guid>
      <description>I finally made it. Hiked all the way up the Malverns and then back again. A total of about 30 km in 6 hours, 45 minutes. Doing these distances does help build up the stamina for the uphill parts of the Kilimanjaro route. However should not neglect the final day when we will descend the mountain where we will do about 20 km which should take us 5-6 hours.
  However am taking quite a beating on my feet, something not completely right with my old hiking boots, a pair of Salomon X Ultra 3 Mid GTX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another training day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/another-training-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 18:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/another-training-day/</guid>
      <description>A glorious sunny Saturday on the May Bank holiday weekend.
This time I started at the southern end at Chase End and worked my way north. Was able to reach Upper Wyche. Still have not reached the goal of doing the whole Malvern Hills up and down (or the other way for that matter).
The hills especially round the southern part of the Malverns were covered in violet, all down to the abundance of bluebells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hike up Pen-y-fan</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/a-hike-up-pen-y-fan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 19:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/a-hike-up-pen-y-fan/</guid>
      <description>A training hike up Pen-y-fan on a Easter weekend.
            </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing Mount Kilimanjaro - The start of the adventure</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/climbing-mount-kilimanjaro-the-start-of-the-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 20:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/kilimanjaro-2019/climbing-mount-kilimanjaro-the-start-of-the-adventure/</guid>
      <description>Image by Greg Montani from Pixabay In this case with booking. I heard of a friend using the company Intrepid Travel several years ago when she went on a fabulous trip to south America.
Have been itching to do something myself and a few weeks ago saw in idea about climbing Mt Kilimanjaro. At 5,895 metres its not an easy endeavour, certainly the highest and the longest I have ever hiked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slovenia, December 2018</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/slovenia-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 14:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2019/slovenia-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>    Some more musically inspired Christmas decorations on Levstik square
          The &amp;#39;flancat&amp;#39; pastry and hot sweet herbal tea
    People in the UK won&amp;#39;t really know about the sport performed here
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lawrenny and Creswell Quay</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/lawrenny-and-creswell-quay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 13:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2018/lawrenny-and-creswell-quay/</guid>
      <description>              Lawrenny woods
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tŷ Canol nature reserve, Pentre Ifan and the original site of the Stonehenge bluestones</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/ty-canol-nature-reserve-pentre-ifan-and-the-original-site-of-the-stonehenge-bluestones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 21:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/ty-canol-nature-reserve-pentre-ifan-and-the-original-site-of-the-stonehenge-bluestones/</guid>
      <description>Haven&amp;rsquo;t been on this little gem for a few years now. Some parts can be quite muddy but everything is repaid with the views of the enchanted forest that is the Tŷ Canol nature reserve. So amazing. The photos don&amp;rsquo;t do it justice.
This walk was a modification of the Pentre Ifan walk from circular Pembrokeshire walks book by Dennis and Jan Kelsall. Only this time I extended it from the Pentre Ifan burial chamber towards the now confirmed site where the Stonehenge bluestones were sourced from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little boat trip</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-little-boat-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 21:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2017/a-little-boat-trip/</guid>
      <description>Went on a little boat trip with some friends on the Cleddau river in Pembrokeshire. They even served us fish &amp;amp; chips and beer and wine. Very cool.
    The skipper awaits
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bohinj still rocks in the winter</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/bohinj-still-rocks-in-the-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 21:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/bohinj-still-rocks-in-the-winter/</guid>
      <description>An all time favourite hiking destination.
  Church of St. John the Baptist in Ribčev Laz
    Vrh nad Želimljami
    Vrh nad Želimljami
    View of Triglav from my easyJet flight back to London Stansted
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ladyclough woods, Ashop valley and Stanage Edge</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/ladyclough-woods-ashop-valley-and-stanage-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 18:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2016/ladyclough-woods-ashop-valley-and-stanage-edge/</guid>
      <description>A nice little tour of the Peak District.
  Ashop valley
    Ladyclough woods
    Ladyclough woods
    Ladyclough woods
    Ladyclough woods
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley
    Ashop valley</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberglasney Garden</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/aberglasney-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 07:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/aberglasney-garden/</guid>
      <description>This lovely estate is about 20 away from Carmarthen on the road to Llandeilo.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uber blunder in Essex</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/uber-blunder-in-essex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2015/uber-blunder-in-essex/</guid>
      <description>Bit the bullet and ordered my first Uber ride in November 2014 when I was in London. It went very well but it was for a very short trip.
The second one was in April 2015 and it was from stansted airport to a nearby b&amp;amp;b about 15 minutes away. I loved the fact that you know beforehand who will be picking you up, what the reg number of the car is and where the car is on a map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luggage FUBAR riding a motorcycle</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2014/luggage-fubar-riding-a-motorcycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 17:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2014/luggage-fubar-riding-a-motorcycle/</guid>
      <description>Had a great trip to the Algarve recently and rented a Honda Shadow motorcycle for a week. On one of the last few days of my stay there I planned a trip to the south-western tip of Portugal - Cabo de São Vicente and Sagres. However all did not go well from my start in Albufeira. As I knew I was going to be on the road for at least an hour, perhaps 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter warmth by croud sourcing</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/winter-warmth-by-croud-sourcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 19:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/winter-warmth-by-croud-sourcing/</guid>
      <description>One thing to note to anyone attempting to hike up the Snežnik mountain is that the place is quite remote. If you set off from Ljubljana the road takes you past Postojna and towards Croatia and you then have to drive on a gravel road for quite some time to get to the Sviščaki village. From there the route takes you through a beautiful bear country forest.
About half an hour or so from the summit I walked onto this clearing where there was a lot of chopped wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krim</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/krim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 19:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/krim/</guid>
      <description>If Krim is covered with clouds in the evening then there will be bad weather tomorrow. If its not then the weather will be fair.
 Well, that what we were told and that is the knowledge we stuck by.
Krim is a 1,107m tall mountain on the southern outskirts of the Ljubljana moors. In all the years I have lived in Slovenia I have never actually been up it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almost ready to go...</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/almost-ready-to-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 08:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/bike-trip-round-the-usa-2013/almost-ready-to-go/</guid>
      <description>Taken on my recent trip to Wales
    Taken on my recent trip to Wales
    Taken on my recent trip to Wales, Caerfai Bay
    Honda Pan-European
    Honda Pan-European
    Honda Pan-European
    A stop at one of my favourite spots, Tan-y-coed
  Later this week I will be living the dream by starting my long-planned motorcycle trip round the US, going into the wild as much as possible, breathing the fresh air, meeting strangers, creating friendships :-D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dust storm in Lancashire</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/dust-storm-in-lancashire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 20:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2013/dust-storm-in-lancashire/</guid>
      <description>Lancashire dirt storm
  This was definitely a first. Not only have I ever seen this meteorological phenomenon, I was never expecting to see it in the UK - the country known for its wet climate.
I was working in a small village in Lancashire but lived on the coast and on my way home I saw these strange dark clouds on the horizon. As I got closer I realised it was clouds of soil and dirt that were being picked up by the strong gusts of wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floreat Salopia</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/floreat-salopia-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 13:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/floreat-salopia-2/</guid>
      <description>Floreat Salopia_ meaning May Shropshire flourish a fitting start of this blog post dedicated to my latest locum job that has taken me to Shrewsbury , the capital of Shropshire . I have never been to Shropshire before and it really was something I needed to amend as it hides some really amazing gems. The most charming, in my opinion, is the before-mentioned medieval capital, about the size of Maribor , that has hundreds of grade listed buildings and lovely narrow streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some more Snowdonia trekking</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/some-more-snowdonia-trekking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 21:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/some-more-snowdonia-trekking/</guid>
      <description>Next to the Watkin path
  Not to repeat myself to many times but I went on a great hiking trip round Snowdonia. Got up way to early and still by the time I came to Nant Gwynant I was still very much in need of sleep. Besides that it was still pouring with rain but there were prospects of sunshine later. So I I did something I haven&amp;rsquo;t so far: crawled in the back of my car, got myself comfortable, opened the windows a little bit and went to sleep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rediscovering the Glyders</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/rediscovering-the-glyders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 07:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2012/rediscovering-the-glyders/</guid>
      <description>Standing on the famous Cantilever on Glyder Fach in Snowdonia
  A couple of years ago I trekked these hills with and came away with a lovely sunburn, sore legs and a great experience. Not unlike this time although I cannot fathom how those UV lights beams were able to penetrate all those clouds yesterday in order to give my skin a damn good uv-light trashing.
The Glyders horseshoe as its also known usually means walking the 4 mountains in one go and this time I did them in this order: Tryfan, Glyer Fach, Glyder Fawr and Y Garn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ski Wednesday</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/ski-wednesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 19:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/ski-wednesday/</guid>
      <description>Krvavec
  My recent trip to Slovenia gave me the repeat opportunity to do some skiing again which I was looking forward of doing on the ski resort of Krvavec. I am proud to report no falls or injuries whatsoever.
The place was absolutely packed, probably due to the fact that it was in that weird time between Christmas and New Year and lots of people had the time off work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Carnedds</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/exploring-the-carnedds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2011 21:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/exploring-the-carnedds/</guid>
      <description>Sunset behind Tryfan
  I returned to to Snowdonia in mid October 2011 to explore the northern third of the Snowdonia range, also known as the Carneddau. They are the most technically demanding part of the Snowdonia range in my opinion but you should not disregard them as there are some really stunning views seen on this range.
When I was returning back to the car park near Llyn Ogwen I was blessed with a spectacular sunset behind the Tryfan mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2011 Three - Day Three - Peak Challenge</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/my-2011-three-peak-challenge-in-three-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 12:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/my-2011-three-peak-challenge-in-three-days/</guid>
      <description>A pit-stop and a warm coffee at Chester M56 services
  OK. My three-peak challenge underway now. One (Snowdon) down, two more to go (Scafell Pike &amp;amp; Ben Nevis). Today&amp;rsquo;s climb on Snowdon was a challenge in itself as it was pissing (yes, not just pouring - PISSING) down with rain. Not one thing I was wearing is currently dry and I am using the car heater to dry as much as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The lake of: Now you see it, now you don&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-lake-of-now-you-see-it-now-you-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 20:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-lake-of-now-you-see-it-now-you-dont/</guid>
      <description>Lake Cerknica
  This is about Lake Cerknica - the largest lake in Slovenia, when its there, of course, part of the Notranjska Regional Park . When its there its about 25 km2, but can reach up to 38 km2. It has a complicated system of communications with the underground reservoirs which means the lake can drain and thus completely disappear. It usually fills up after the autumn rains and the spring thaw, and is empty round May and June (sometimes even in winter) so I was lucky to see it when I was there on June 16th.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rakov Škocjan</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/rakov-skocjan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 19:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/rakov-skocjan/</guid>
      <description>Rakov Škocjan
  Here is an example of an area I remember visiting as a child and have only vague recollections of it. It is a stunning area in the karst region of Slovenia - the same region where the world famous Postojna caves and Škocjan caves are located, however the Rakov Škocjan park albeit less known to the regular tourist, is still a must see.
  Rakov Škocjan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Miramare estate</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-miramare-estate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-miramare-estate/</guid>
      <description>This is a stunning castle with surrounding estate close to the northern Italian city of Trieste , close to border with Slovenia .
The Miramare Castle is a stunning Carl Junker designed 19th century castle near the northeastern Italian city of Trieste and was built from 1856 to 1860 for Austrian Archduke Ferdinand Maximilian and his wife, Charlotte of Belgium, later Emperor Maximilian I and Empress Carlota of Mexico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patriarchal Basilica of Aquileia</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/patriarchal-basilica-of-aquileia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 19:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/patriarchal-basilica-of-aquileia/</guid>
      <description>Oglej or Aquileia in Italian is a small village in north-eastern Italy close to the holiday town of Grado (Slovenian: Gradež)
  It is the home of the Patriarchal Basilica of Aquileia which houses the largest and stunning piece of mosaic I have ever seen. Restaurateurs have manufactured an elevated platform and glass walkway inside the basilica allowing you to still walk in the cathedral without walking and ruining the precious mosaic on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Savica falls and Lake Bohinj</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-savica-falls-and-lake-bohinj/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 19:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/the-savica-falls-and-lake-bohinj/</guid>
      <description>This is an old favourite of mine and apparently for many Brits as well as during my short visit there saw countless UK reg cars on the roads.
The Savica waterfall is part of the Sava Bohinjka river which is joined by the Sava Dolinka near Radovljica to form the Sava river . That in turns flows into the Danube at Belgrade which discharges into the Black Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing the M25 car park</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/experiencing-the-m25-car-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 18:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/experiencing-the-m25-car-park/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1807&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;620&amp;rdquo;]   M25 parking lot on December 18th Photo: TOMMY HINDLEY[/caption]
There were plenty of warnings about possible weather problems before I set off from Haverfordwest in the SW Wales to Stansted airport on December 18th. There was very little snow in Pembrokeshire and the airport was open. There were absolutely no problems up to the M4 exit for Slough .
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1773&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;225&amp;rdquo;]   Photo taken on my iPhone of the M25 standstill[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 6 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-6-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 17:59:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-6-of-6/</guid>
      <description>Tuesday. Almost not worth mentioning as I was going to go back home to Haverfordwest . The train from Paddington was strikingly fast and it looked like we were in Bristol in no time. It feels like ages when driving.
However I was supposed to change trains in Newport, Gwent and they have done some modifications to the station and platform assignments meaning I had to cross to the other side using lots of steps to reach the footbridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 5 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-5-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 17:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-5-of-6/</guid>
      <description>Saint Paul&amp;#39;s Cathedral
  Monday. Did some more walking round London and did the touristy view of St. Paul&amp;rsquo;s Cathedral. The Fat Tyre bike tour guide told me that the view from the top of the cathedral was much more impressive than from the London eye. I surely was not disappointed. The tour was not that bad.
  Village Deli in Bermondsey
  The one thing I wanted to do on this day is to go for lunch in Bermondsey .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 4 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-4-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 16:16:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-4-of-6/</guid>
      <description>BT Tower captured from Oxford Street
  Sunday. Nothing much planned for this day. Did do some shopping but came to Oxford street to early – nobody told me they opened the shops at twelve so I spent some hard earned money at a well-know American coffee franchise called Stardollars or something. The best was left for last as I went to the Natural History Museum and put on a pair of skates after about 17 or 18 years and didn&amp;rsquo;t fall once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 3 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-3-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 15:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-3-of-6/</guid>
      <description>Westminster Hall
  This was a Saturday and the big part of the day was dedicated to the John Rutter &amp;rsquo;s Christmas Celebration at the Royal Albert Hall . This was the second one I have attended and even though the last one I went to was last year it did not feel like a repeat from the previous year. The only difference was to be the Christmas dinner I signed-up</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 2 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-2-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2011 23:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2011/london-visit-2010-day-2-of-6/</guid>
      <description>You know when you sleep in a strange bed and it takes a night or two before you get used to it. That was exactly what I was doing when at about 6am the first morning the hotel, where I was staying, had its fire alarms go off. When I got into the hall outside my room I saw a lot of sleepy-looking heads popping out from behind the doors trying to find out what the hell was going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit 2010 – day 1 of 6</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/london-visit-2010-day-1-of-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 08:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/london-visit-2010-day-1-of-6/</guid>
      <description>London Paddington station during rush hour
  The trip I did last year took quite a bit out of me as I took the car from the deepest and darkest :-) parts of Wales right down the M4 to central London. Now this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be otherwise to bad but for the whole visit being very active and at the end of it was completely exhausted. Not to mention the cold I was nursing at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of the autumn Pembrokeshire snow 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/some-of-the-autumn-pembrokeshire-snow-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 20:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/some-of-the-autumn-pembrokeshire-snow-2010/</guid>
      <description>These photos were taken on a hike to Pentre Ifan this last weekend.
  Pentre Ifan in Pembrokeshire
    Carn Ingli in Pembrokeshire as seen from Pentre Ifan
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterfall of the Snow</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/waterfall-of-the-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 06:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/waterfall-of-the-snow/</guid>
      <description>Fullers Falls - Sgwd y Pannwr
  This hike is worth talking about as it takes you round some spectacular views in the Brecon Beacons.
When I did the hike round Cwm Gwesyn the guide books told us about waterfalls but you saw was actually very small - especially compared to the waterfalls seen on this hike between Ystradfellte and Pontneddfechan.
One of the highlights of the walk is the fact that you can walk under one of the waterfalls names Waterfall of the Snow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tragična zgodba Tommya Jonesa</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/tragicna-zgodba-tommya-jonesa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 19:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/tragicna-zgodba-tommya-jonesa/</guid>
      <description>Gospa Hamer, žena vrtnarja v majhni južno-valežanski vasici, naj bi ponoči sanjala o dečku, ki se je izgubil slab mesec poprej. Ko se je le opogumila in prepričala moža, da ji pomaga, se je 2. septembra leta 1900 skupaj z nekaj sorodniki odpravila na lastno iskalno akcijo. Ko je skupina z gospo Hamer na čelu prispela do grebena nad jezerom Cwm llwch, okoli pol kilometra zahodno od vrha gore Pen-y-fan, je gospa Hammer naenkrat zakričala od groze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing the eminence, and then some</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/climbing-the-eminence-and-then-some/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 19:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/climbing-the-eminence-and-then-some/</guid>
      <description>My original plan for this days hike was Y-Garn but that soon changed once I reached the peak and gazed upon the inviting summits of Glyder Fawr and Glyder Fach. As if that was not enough and after all the struggle of descending off Glyder Fach I made a silly move and ascended up Tryfan. Now for those who haven&amp;rsquo;t been up this mountain I must tell you it more resembles a high stack of very big rocks that in many cases precariously lean on each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cwm Gwesyn and the Llyn Brianne reservoir</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</guid>
      <description>This is marked as the toughest walk in the Brecon Becons &amp;amp; South Wales book and it turned out to be living up to its name. The most difficult part was trying to not get lost on Bryn Rhudd at the same time as not loosing interest in the walk as well. The views on there are almost desert-like, nothing but dried grass and boggy moors. Even the sheep are sensible enough not to stray that far from the valleys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stranded sheep in the Blue Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 21:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>The Sunday between Christmas and the New Year I spent hiking around Pembrokeshire and this time I went for walk no. 12 (Around Ynys Barry) taken from the book mentioned in some of my previous posts There is a local attraction called the Blue Lagoon that is just a few minutes away from the Aber Eiddy (also known as Abereiddy) car park where the walk originates from. The lagoon is actually an old man-made slate mining pit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pembrokeshire snow in January 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</guid>
      <description>Had a big snowstorm last night that covered Pembrokeshire with a bit of snow. These photos taken from a hike up to the highest peak in the Preseli hills - Foel Cwmcerwyn . Very windy at the top!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The winter fear of December 18 &amp; 19</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-winter-fear-of-december-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 21:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-winter-fear-of-december-18/</guid>
      <description>After all the worries about traveling from Haverfordwest to Stansted the 5 1/2 hour trip went fine. Blue skies in most of the Wales part, the first snow on the M4 spotted about 6 miles west of the exit for Slough .
The roads are gritted and the only delay was on the M4 exit for the M25 . It looked like a Smart car caught fire. It was being extinguished on the side of the motorway just as I was passing by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 4 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-4-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 19:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-4-of-4/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1453&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;720&amp;rdquo;]   A shark in the big tank in the London Aquarium[/caption]
Not feeling very well in the morning of the last day, this cold has been getting the better of me and running around London does not help it getting any better. Drugging-up with anti-inflammatories not helped either.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1454&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignright&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;225&amp;rdquo;]   The London Eye - close to the top[/caption]
First port of call was the London eye I booked the previous day on-line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 3 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-3-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 23:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-3-of-4/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1450&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;640&amp;rdquo;]   The Cabinet War Rooms[/caption]
I started the day a bit more relaxing by taking a slow breakfast at the local Starbucks at London Bridge station opposite Guy&amp;rsquo;s Hospital. A friend told me I had to try the frappucino and their panninis. The guy at the counter asked me twice if I was sure about the frappucino? It is apparently and ice-cold drink and it was the middle of December plus I was bearing a very deep and cold-ridden voice so I wisely opted for a warmer beverage - in this case for a mocha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 2 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-2-of-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 22:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-2-of-4/</guid>
      <description>After only sleeping a few hours as I only went to bed at 4 am as a consequence from the previous night&amp;rsquo;s walkabout London I had a Fat Tyre bike tour planned for the Saturday morning. The tour takes place on bicycles you get from the tour company and it starts at 11am just outside the Queensway underground station. Its a great way to see the city as you can see different parts of it without walking large distances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London visit - day 1 of 4</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2009 18:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/london-visit-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I soon realised my satnav is going to make me drive down the M4 right into the centre of London - no ifs or butts. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad really, all I had to do is to imagine I was driving downtown Ljubljana - just on a much bigger scale. And it really went very well except at the very end one of the roads was closed and I had to make up a detour on my own - only to get myself even more stuck into the dreaded London rush-hour traffic jams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got bullied by three horses</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/how-i-got-bullied-by-three-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 10:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/how-i-got-bullied-by-three-horses/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1407&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo;]   This is not a photo from the incident[/caption]
Recently I haven not been writing about my treks round Pembrokeshire and how I have been working my way through the &amp;ldquo;Walking in Pembrokeshire &amp;rdquo; guide. I&amp;rsquo;ve done so many now I have been repeating some of them two to three times. This last walk I did for the first time and is worth mentioning as it was one of the more unusual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snemanje Robina Hooda - malce bližje</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-malce-blizje/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 18:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-malce-blizje/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1329&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;446&amp;rdquo;]   Slika z BBC strani, avtorja Scotty[/caption]
Včeraj sem šel spet malo na ogled do lokacije snemanja novega filma o Robinu Hoodu na obali Freshwater West in zadeve so se precej spremenile od prejšnjega tedna, ko sem bil nazadnje tam. Varnostnikov ni bilo veliko in tokrat so me vsaj spustili na plažo, kljub temu, da je na tam potekalo snemanje. Povsod sami statisti, večinoma v horizontali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snemanje Robina Hooda - od daleč</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 19:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</guid>
      <description>V mesecu juniju 2009 so pričeli nedaleč od tod s snemanjem naslednje filmske upodobitve princa tatov - Robina Hooda.
Lokacija, kjer poteka snemanje, se imenuje Freshwater West in gre za eno lepših plaž v Pembrokeshire -ju in Wales-u nasploh. Tu so pejšnji mesec celo snemali naslednji film o Harryu Potterju. Produkcija za Robina Hooda pa je precej večja in vključuje veliko več ljudi in opreme. Pred tedni so imeli v bližnji dvorani avdicijo za statiste in prijaviti se jih je hotelo veliko več, kolikor je bilo mest na voljo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking the hills of Snowdon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 09:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I moved to Wales 2 years ago I had a quiet wish to climb the highest peak in this country - Snowdon. Last weekend was showing to be a perfect opportunity to fulfil that wish. I was working only till 12 pm and the forecast was for sunshine and high temperatures stretching way into the following week. Getting some good literature , so you know what your are doing, is very advisable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hill of Angels</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</guid>
      <description>Looking down towards Cwm mawr
  What a thoroughly enjoyable way to spend a March Sunday. In fact it was so nice I wish the hike would have lasted a bit longer. Instead I took the opportunity to sit and enjoy the sunshine on the wooden bench by the Sychbant car park were this walk starts and ends.
The walk (no. 39: Mynydd Caregog and Carn Ingli) starts off with a nice steep hill and then should continue in a conifer forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhydwilym</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/rhydwilym/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 19:26:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/rhydwilym/</guid>
      <description>entrance to the mine
  As the book states this is a walk where you can see lots of nice views and hardly meet anyone. And it was true for me. Only people I met were some farmers on a field, however the fact that I did the walk on a Tuesday afternoon might have had something to do with it.
I was especially surprised to see an actual waterfall, not very big but a waterfall nonetheless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Treffgarne Mountain</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</guid>
      <description>This walk seemed the muddiest of them all, in fact I am wandering how exactly to wash my walking shoes and the washing machine is getting to be the favourite. This is the walk no. 32 and can easily be combined with no. 33 (Treffgarne Gorge) as they both start from the same point. That was actually my plan but my walking shoes got filled with lots of lovely mud hindering any furter hikes that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Ryanair website really so bad</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/is-the-ryainair-website-really-so-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 18:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/is-the-ryainair-website-really-so-bad/</guid>
      <description>According to my experience, yes. I tell all Ryanair visitors in advance that this here is my personal opinion and will not allow the publication of rude comments from anyone.
I had the misfortune of booking my flight today only to be confronted with an error just at the point you would least like it - after purchase.
A while ago I found a blog post about a session problem with the Ryanair website here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carn Llidi</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 11:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</guid>
      <description>Coetan Arthur burial chamber on St Davids Head
  OK, same book used from the last walk , but this time it was walk no. 11: St David&amp;rsquo;s Head and Carn Llidi. You start off at Whitesands near St David which is convenient as there is lots of parking available - you will be charged parking if you come during the tourist season.
The Carn Lidi hill is a prominent feature in southern Pembrokeshire and you can see it from miles away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stonehenge = Made in the Preselis</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/stonehenge-made-in-the-preselis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 18:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/stonehenge-made-in-the-preselis/</guid>
      <description>This morning was going to be a another great day for hiking as the skies were clear and there was no rain forecast for the whole day. I was, again, following the great book Walking in Pembrokeshire - 41 circular walks in the National park. By the way, this was walk no 21: Carn Menyn and the »Bluestones«.
It took me a bit to find the correct site for parking as I kept switching between the book and the Ordnance survey map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 07:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>I have tried to visit this place before but the last time got a bit disappointed as there was the standard parking fee . Today was a very good time to see the place, sunny and not a lot of people on it. Oh yes, and the parking was free. By the way, I am all for conservation and good old cash goes a long way in conservation but ripping local of so that they can use the local nature is just wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sands of speed</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 16:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/sands-of-speed/</guid>
      <description>This is the name of a 7 mile (11 km) stretch of sandy beach located on the south Wales coastline between Tenby and Swansea . The most impressive feature of this beach is its flatness and straightness at such a long length. You can see the satellite view below.
In the early 20th century the sands were often used as a racing course and later, in the 1920s, it was used for land speed records .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The red dragon will lead the way</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-red-dragon-will-lead-the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2008 19:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/the-red-dragon-will-lead-the-way/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_736&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;576&amp;rdquo;]   The Pierhead building in Cardiff Bay[/caption]
Always wanted to see the capital of Wales but always ended up just drive pass it on the M4. The closest I ever got to the actual city centre was to visit the local Ikea store while I was still in the process of furnishing my small flat in Haverfordwest.
Here are some more detailed instructions for those who might want to see it also but don&amp;rsquo;t know how to get there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenby</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_656&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;800&amp;rdquo;]   Tenby harbour with the Quay on left, lifeboat station above it, Castle Hill in the centre top[/caption]
I have put it off for a long time but a sightee-er to Tenby was well due. The town of Tenby lies on the south Pembrokeshire coast and if leaving from Haverfordwest can take the road across the Cledau bridge or you can, by saving the 75p bridge toll and, depriving the Pembrokeshire County Council :-), go through Canaston Bridge .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schmap-ing me</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/schmaping-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 19:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/schmaping-me/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_639&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;]   The photo of Bristol Cathedral chosen for the fifth edition of the Schmap Bristol Guide[/caption]
I received a mail today from an on-line publisher of digital travel guides called Schmap that my photo of Bristol Cathedral was chosen to be included in the fifth edition of the Schmap Bristol Guide .
I received an e-mail a while ago saying that the photo was short-listed for it and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think my photos were good enough for somebody to publish them in a guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PST od Johnstona do Neylanda</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/pst-od-johnstona-do-neylanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2008 12:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/pst-od-johnstona-do-neylanda/</guid>
      <description>Prejšnji torek sem delal samo pol dneva in sem izkoristil to priložnost da sem končno opravil pešpot od Johnstona, kraja kjer živim, do Neylanda . Oba kraja sta namreč povezana s precej lepo kolesarsko stezo, ki pa je odprta tudi za pešce. Pot je približno dolga 6,5 km in se vije po prelepi valežanski pokrajini. Sicer valežanska pot ne bi bila prava, če ne bi bila levo in desno obdana s kako ograjo ali nasipom in tudi ta ni izjema, amapk pustmo to - dan je bil lep in dejmo pot pot noge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
