<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>walks on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/walks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in walks on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 20:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/walks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cwm Gwesyn and the Llyn Brianne reservoir</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/cwm-gwsyn-and-the-llyn-brianne-reservoir/</guid>
      <description>This is marked as the toughest walk in the Brecon Becons &amp;amp; South Wales book and it turned out to be living up to its name. The most difficult part was trying to not get lost on Bryn Rhudd at the same time as not loosing interest in the walk as well. The views on there are almost desert-like, nothing but dried grass and boggy moors. Even the sheep are sensible enough not to stray that far from the valleys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trekking the hills of Snowdon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 09:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I moved to Wales 2 years ago I had a quiet wish to climb the highest peak in this country - Snowdon. Last weekend was showing to be a perfect opportunity to fulfil that wish. I was working only till 12 pm and the forecast was for sunshine and high temperatures stretching way into the following week. Getting some good literature , so you know what your are doing, is very advisable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hill of Angels</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</guid>
      <description>Looking down towards Cwm mawr
  What a thoroughly enjoyable way to spend a March Sunday. In fact it was so nice I wish the hike would have lasted a bit longer. Instead I took the opportunity to sit and enjoy the sunshine on the wooden bench by the Sychbant car park were this walk starts and ends.
The walk (no. 39: Mynydd Caregog and Carn Ingli) starts off with a nice steep hill and then should continue in a conifer forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carn Llidi</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 11:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</guid>
      <description>Coetan Arthur burial chamber on St Davids Head
  OK, same book used from the last walk , but this time it was walk no. 11: St David&amp;rsquo;s Head and Carn Llidi. You start off at Whitesands near St David which is convenient as there is lots of parking available - you will be charged parking if you come during the tourist season.
The Carn Lidi hill is a prominent feature in southern Pembrokeshire and you can see it from miles away.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
