<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recreation on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/recreation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recreation on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 09:56:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/recreation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trekking the hills of Snowdon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 09:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/trekking-the-hills-of-snowdon/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I moved to Wales 2 years ago I had a quiet wish to climb the highest peak in this country - Snowdon. Last weekend was showing to be a perfect opportunity to fulfil that wish. I was working only till 12 pm and the forecast was for sunshine and high temperatures stretching way into the following week. Getting some good literature , so you know what your are doing, is very advisable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hill of Angels</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2009 17:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/the-hill-of-angels/</guid>
      <description>Looking down towards Cwm mawr
  What a thoroughly enjoyable way to spend a March Sunday. In fact it was so nice I wish the hike would have lasted a bit longer. Instead I took the opportunity to sit and enjoy the sunshine on the wooden bench by the Sychbant car park were this walk starts and ends.
The walk (no. 39: Mynydd Caregog and Carn Ingli) starts off with a nice steep hill and then should continue in a conifer forest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiing on Vogel</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skiing-on-vogel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 20:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skiing-on-vogel/</guid>
      <description>Started off while it was still dark. Plan A was going to ski on Krvavec. No plan B at that time. Just as we left Cerklje there was a suspicious hold-up in the traffic which turned out to be due to the great number of cars - all heading for the same ski resort. My friend and I parked just soon after Cerklje , where the buses usually park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive London for a day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I did what I wanted to do for a long while - to actually skydive in the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting it off for a long time, lately mostly due to the weather we have been having. Last weekend the weather was OK, no flu lingering in the background and no lameness in any of the legs :-) The Skydive London dropzone is situated about 3 hours drive away from Haverfordwest , adjacent to the town of Swindon .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
