<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>skydiving on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/skydiving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in skydiving on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 17:05:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/categories/skydiving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netheravon 25. September 2009</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/netheravon-25-september-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 17:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/netheravon-25-september-2009/</guid>
      <description>Back here again, desperately trying to find an FS-1 coach to get my FS-1 license done. Only did one jump today as I developed one very nasty headache and it seems this is one of the rare times I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring any painkillers along.
Oh, what fun ;-)
Beside that the Friday night jumps will commence soon, preparations are under way as I speak (I mean write).
KPICASA_GALLERY(Netheravon)
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydiving after 11 months</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/skydiving-after-11-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 12:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/skydiving-after-11-months/</guid>
      <description>After waiting for 11 months and practically giving up on the notion of jumping out of a plane for the foreseeable future. The given opportunity came last week, Friday off and a sunny forecast. Great weekend.
Managed 7 jumps the Netheravon DZ. Now all I am left to do is to get my FS1 licence as its needed in the UK for jumping in groups.
Didn&amp;rsquo;t take any photos, was a bit worried would get nicked as the DZ is situated on an active military base (technically its an airfield camp ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 2</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2008 21:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206-2/</guid>
      <description>I have now managed to send off the container to the manufacturer Aerodyne in Florida . I have just driven back from Swansea where I send off the container through a DHL ServicePoint location in the Parc Tawe Staples shop. Great service, if you ask me, as you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay a high price to have your packed shipped and you also choose what boy its going to be sent in - the price of shipment depends on the size of the box, but with a upper weight limit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ooops, or how I ripped my container on a Cessna 206, part 1</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 19:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/ooops-or-how-i-ripped-my-container-on-a-cessna-206/</guid>
      <description>My recent visit to the motherland gave me the opportunity for yet another skydiving session, I joined my instructor and mentor Aleš Debeljak from the Paranoia skydiving school.
All went well and on the third jump of the second day just as I exited the Cessna 206 I apparently managed to hook my rig on the side of the door which resulted in a nasty tear in my container on the reserve parachute flap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5 in Deland - back in the air again</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-5-in-deland-back-in-the-air-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2008 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-5-in-deland-back-in-the-air-again/</guid>
      <description>The morning had low clouds but we hoped that they would soon lift and that we would see blue skies again - unfortunately this took much longer than first predicted as we started jumping at about 1PM.
As it was a Sunday most of the skydivers wanted to make the most of the day and the DZ became very busy as there were 3 planes flying at any given time (Twin Otter, PAC 820, Skyvan or Porter), today we saw the first appearance of the Skyvan .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive Sebastian</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skydive-sebastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/skydive-sebastian/</guid>
      <description>As we woke this morning we could only take a depressing glance out of the window and despair over the rubbish weather we had. It was bucketing down. We had to decide either to stay in the house, go on a (inside) sightseeing tour, or drive to a DZ that does not have bad weather. We chose on the latter and decided to go to Skydive Sebastian - a DZ located in the Florida town called Sebastian (duh) just over 2 hours drive from Deland, passing Titusville and Cape Canaveral on the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 at Deland</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-2-at-deland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2008 02:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-2-at-deland/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have got my reserve deployment out of the way I can get to some good and proper skydiving. Managed to get the record number of jumps for a day - 5 and I could have done at least one more but I had to arrange another rental car for our group.
The picture on the left is showing our makeshift hangar - the flag has now been moved to a proper flag post close to the boarding zone - pics to follow :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 in Orlando</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 01:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/day-3-in-orlando/</guid>
      <description>This is getting to be really tough. Last nights session started at midnight and I somewhat remember going to bed at 2am. This morning there are another three sessions, the first one on which starts at 9am. I am well and truly sore all over and hadn&amp;rsquo;t had this much physical exercise in a good few years.
Most of us, who are doing RW work in the tunnel don&amp;rsquo;t have much time to do anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A great tragedy</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/a-great-tragedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 13:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/a-great-tragedy/</guid>
      <description>As usual some of the media outlets are taking a completely wrong ignorant spin on this genuine and sad tragedy.
Slovenia lost a great pilot Viktor Bečan (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo;). My sincere condolences go to his family. My hopes for a quick recovery go to the surviving co-pilot Savo Medved
Photo on left featuring the &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo; made by Lubi in Novo mesto (Prečna) in June 2007.
Slovenia lost a legend among skydiving planes the &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo; - Antonov 2 from the Paranoia Skydiving school (part of the ŠOLT organization) that fulfilled the dreams of many skydivers in becoming the vessel for them to do their first skydive jumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>»Fata« and »Som« have left us</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/fata-and-som-have-left-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2008 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/fata-and-som-have-left-us/</guid>
      <description>I must sadly inform you that the Antonov-2 airplane (we lovingly called &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo;) from which I learned how to skydive and did many jumps, the most recent ones in September 2007, crashed in the mountains near Trbovlje at about 1pm local time.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_350&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;150&amp;rdquo;]   Photo taken by Daniel Zavratnik in Bovec in August 2007. Viktor Bečan a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Som&amp;rdquo; is the chap on the left in a green t-shirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skydive London for a day</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/skydive-london-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I did what I wanted to do for a long while - to actually skydive in the UK. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting it off for a long time, lately mostly due to the weather we have been having. Last weekend the weather was OK, no flu lingering in the background and no lameness in any of the legs :-) The Skydive London dropzone is situated about 3 hours drive away from Haverfordwest , adjacent to the town of Swindon .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return to skydiving</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/return-to-skydiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/return-to-skydiving/</guid>
      <description>After a one year sebaticle I finally got the chance to do some skydiving again. The best thing about it, besides, of course, skydiving, was that I could do it at my old home drop zone Prečna in Novo mesto in the southern part of Slovenia. The other good part was that I could jump from the old Antonov 2 (the one we use bares the nickname &amp;ldquo;Fata&amp;rdquo; and here is a picture of it in action).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bodyflight Bedford indoor skydiving [or how to fly around a room and not having a hangover the next day]</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/bodyflight-bedford-indoor-skydiving-or-how-to-fly-around-a-room-and-not-having-a-hangover-the-next-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2007 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2007/bodyflight-bedford-indoor-skydiving-or-how-to-fly-around-a-room-and-not-having-a-hangover-the-next-day/</guid>
      <description>It was a great day probably more suitable for outdoor skydiving than indoor skydiving. I set of from home early Saturday morning and arrived at Bedford five and a half hours later after stupidly ignoring my satnav and adding another hour to my already long journey. The Bodyflight facility is situated in a generally abandoned ex-military complex outside of Bedford near the A6. I heard it was used to do tests for the Concorde.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
