<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pembrokeshire on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</title>
    <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/pembrokeshire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pembrokeshire on Martin&#39;s Blog 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 21:01:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog3.mcdowell.si/tags/pembrokeshire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stranded sheep in the Blue Lagoon</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 21:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/stranded-sheep-in-the-blue-lagoon/</guid>
      <description>The Sunday between Christmas and the New Year I spent hiking around Pembrokeshire and this time I went for walk no. 12 (Around Ynys Barry) taken from the book mentioned in some of my previous posts There is a local attraction called the Blue Lagoon that is just a few minutes away from the Aber Eiddy (also known as Abereiddy) car park where the walk originates from. The lagoon is actually an old man-made slate mining pit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pembrokeshire snow in January 2010</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2010/pembrokeshire-snow-in-january-2010/</guid>
      <description>Had a big snowstorm last night that covered Pembrokeshire with a bit of snow. These photos taken from a hike up to the highest peak in the Preseli hills - Foel Cwmcerwyn . Very windy at the top!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got bullied by three horses</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/how-i-got-bullied-by-three-horses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 10:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/how-i-got-bullied-by-three-horses/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1407&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo;]   This is not a photo from the incident[/caption]
Recently I haven not been writing about my treks round Pembrokeshire and how I have been working my way through the &amp;ldquo;Walking in Pembrokeshire &amp;rdquo; guide. I&amp;rsquo;ve done so many now I have been repeating some of them two to three times. This last walk I did for the first time and is worth mentioning as it was one of the more unusual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snemanje Robina Hooda - malce bližje</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-malce-blizje/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 18:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-malce-blizje/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_1329&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;446&amp;rdquo;]   Slika z BBC strani, avtorja Scotty[/caption]
Včeraj sem šel spet malo na ogled do lokacije snemanja novega filma o Robinu Hoodu na obali Freshwater West in zadeve so se precej spremenile od prejšnjega tedna, ko sem bil nazadnje tam. Varnostnikov ni bilo veliko in tokrat so me vsaj spustili na plažo, kljub temu, da je na tam potekalo snemanje. Povsod sami statisti, večinoma v horizontali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snemanje Robina Hooda - od daleč</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2009 19:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/snemanje-robina-hooda-od-dalec/</guid>
      <description>V mesecu juniju 2009 so pričeli nedaleč od tod s snemanjem naslednje filmske upodobitve princa tatov - Robina Hooda.
Lokacija, kjer poteka snemanje, se imenuje Freshwater West in gre za eno lepših plaž v Pembrokeshire -ju in Wales-u nasploh. Tu so pejšnji mesec celo snemali naslednji film o Harryu Potterju. Produkcija za Robina Hooda pa je precej večja in vključuje veliko več ljudi in opreme. Pred tedni so imeli v bližnji dvorani avdicijo za statiste in prijaviti se jih je hotelo veliko več, kolikor je bilo mest na voljo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Treffgarne Mountain</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2009 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/great-treffgarne-mountain/</guid>
      <description>This walk seemed the muddiest of them all, in fact I am wandering how exactly to wash my walking shoes and the washing machine is getting to be the favourite. This is the walk no. 32 and can easily be combined with no. 33 (Treffgarne Gorge) as they both start from the same point. That was actually my plan but my walking shoes got filled with lots of lovely mud hindering any furter hikes that day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carn Llidi</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 11:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/carn-llidi/</guid>
      <description>Coetan Arthur burial chamber on St Davids Head
  OK, same book used from the last walk , but this time it was walk no. 11: St David&amp;rsquo;s Head and Carn Llidi. You start off at Whitesands near St David which is convenient as there is lots of parking available - you will be charged parking if you come during the tourist season.
The Carn Lidi hill is a prominent feature in southern Pembrokeshire and you can see it from miles away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stonehenge = Made in the Preselis</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/stonehenge-made-in-the-preselis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 18:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2009/stonehenge-made-in-the-preselis/</guid>
      <description>This morning was going to be a another great day for hiking as the skies were clear and there was no rain forecast for the whole day. I was, again, following the great book Walking in Pembrokeshire - 41 circular walks in the National park. By the way, this was walk no 21: Carn Menyn and the »Bluestones«.
It took me a bit to find the correct site for parking as I kept switching between the book and the Ordnance survey map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marloes Sands</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 07:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/marloes-sands/</guid>
      <description>I have tried to visit this place before but the last time got a bit disappointed as there was the standard parking fee . Today was a very good time to see the place, sunny and not a lot of people on it. Oh yes, and the parking was free. By the way, I am all for conservation and good old cash goes a long way in conservation but ripping local of so that they can use the local nature is just wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tenby</title>
      <link>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2008 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog3.mcdowell.si/post/2008/tenby/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_656&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;800&amp;rdquo;]   Tenby harbour with the Quay on left, lifeboat station above it, Castle Hill in the centre top[/caption]
I have put it off for a long time but a sightee-er to Tenby was well due. The town of Tenby lies on the south Pembrokeshire coast and if leaving from Haverfordwest can take the road across the Cledau bridge or you can, by saving the 75p bridge toll and, depriving the Pembrokeshire County Council :-), go through Canaston Bridge .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
